<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Golang on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golang on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 21:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy a Go (Golang) backend with a React frontend separately on Kubernetes - Part One</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/07/23/kubernetes-deploy-golang-react-apps-separately-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/07/23/kubernetes-deploy-golang-react-apps-separately-part1/</guid>
      <description>Intro Welcome. This is a longer post about how to deploy a Go backend with a React frontend on Kubernetes as separate entities. Instead of the usual compiled together single binary Go application, we are going to separate the two. Why? Because usually a React frontend is just a &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; SPA app with very little requirements in terms of resources, while the Go backend does most of the leg work, requiring a lot more resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do a good code review</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/05/11/good-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/05/11/good-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
This time, I would like to talk a little bit about code reviews.
How do you do code reviews? Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to share it in the comments.
How do I do code reviews? Well read on if you would like to know.
The Top Down approach If I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with a small code change, a couple of lines here and there in the odd file first, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to understand why the review is there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make SPA refresh work with a Go backend</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/02/17/making-spa-refresh-work-with-go-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/02/17/making-spa-refresh-work-with-go-backend/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Today I would like to share a quick &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; for a problem I&amp;rsquo;ve seen popping up here and there.
That is, if you have a react frontend which is a SPA app but you still want refresh to work. What do I mean by that? Consider the following&amp;hellip;
The problem You have a SPA app with a react router which navigates the user around. The app calls to a backend api which serves content of some kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Practical Go workshop from Dave Cheney</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/10/practical-go-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/10/practical-go-summary/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
So there is this workshop from Dave Cheney.
And I thought I&amp;rsquo;d draw a sort of summary of that workshop.
Right-click-&amp;gt;Open Image for higher resolution.
Cheers, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efferent and Afferent metrics in Go</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/04/21/efferent-and-afferent-metrics-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/04/21/efferent-and-afferent-metrics-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks!
Today I would like to write about a metric that I read in a book called Clean Architecture from Robert Cecil Martin ( Uncle Bob ).
Abstract The metrics I mean are Efferent and Afferent coupling in packages. So you, dear reader, don&amp;rsquo;t have to navigate away from this page, here are the descriptions pasted in:
Afferent couplings (Ca): The number of classes in other packages that depend upon classes within the package is an indicator of the package&amp;rsquo;s responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go SSH with Host Key Verification</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/02/17/go-ssh-with-host-key-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/02/17/go-ssh-with-host-key-verification/</guid>
      <description>Go SSH with Host Key Verification</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensive tutorial on go-plugin.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/10/29/go-plugin-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 07:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/10/29/go-plugin-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>go-plugin tutorial</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace with a new Plugin System</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/09/17/furnace-plugin-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 07:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/09/17/furnace-plugin-update/</guid>
      <description>Furnace plugins</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/04/16/building-furnace-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 09:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/04/16/building-furnace-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1. Part 2. Part 3.
In this part we are going to talk about Unit Testing Furnace and how to work some magic with AWS and Go.
Mock Stub Fake Dummy Canned Unit testing in Go usually follows the Dependency Injection model of dealing with Mocks and Stubs.
## DI
Dependency Inject in short is one object supplying the dependencies of another object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/22/building-furnace-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 12:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/22/building-furnace-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1. Part 2. Part 4.
In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the experimental plugin system of Furnace.
Go Experimental Plugins Since Go 1.8 was released, an exciting and new feature was introduced called a Plug-in system. This system works with dynamic libraries built with a special switch to go build. These libraries, .so or .dylib (later), are than loaded and once that succeeds, specific functions can be called from them (symbol resolution).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/19/building-furnace-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 12:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/19/building-furnace-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1, Part 3, Part 4
In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the AWS Go SDK and begin do dissect the intricacies of Furnace.
AWS SDK Fortunately, the Go SDK for AWS is quiet verbose and littered with examples of all sorts. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it less complex and less cryptic at times. I&amp;rsquo;m here to lift some of the early confusions, in hopes that I can help someone to avoid wasting time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/16/building-furnace-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 21:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/16/building-furnace-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Other posts: Part 2, Part 3, Part 4.
Building Furnace: Part 1 Intro Hi folks.
This is the first part of a 4 part series which talks about the process of building a middlish sized project in Go, with AWS. Including Unit testing and a experimental plugin feature.
The first part will talk about the AWS services used in brief and will contain a basic description for those who are not familiar with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do Google Sign-In with Go - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/11/02/google-signin-with-go-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/11/02/google-signin-with-go-part2/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi Folks.
This is a follow up on my previous post about Google Sign-In. In this post we will discover what to do with the information retrieved in the first encounter, which you can find here: Google Sign-In Part 1.
Forewords The Project Everything I did in the first post, and that I&amp;rsquo;m going to do in this example, can be found in this project: Google-OAuth-Go-Sample.
Just to recap, we left off previously on the point where we successfully obtained information about the user, with a secure token and a session initiated with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do Google sign-in with Go</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/06/12/google-signin-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/06/12/google-signin-with-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I would like to write up a step - by - step guide with a sample web app on how to do Google Sign-In and authorization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
