<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 21:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy a Go (Golang) backend with a React frontend separately on Kubernetes - Part One</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/07/23/kubernetes-deploy-golang-react-apps-separately-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/07/23/kubernetes-deploy-golang-react-apps-separately-part1/</guid>
      <description>Intro Welcome. This is a longer post about how to deploy a Go backend with a React frontend on Kubernetes as separate entities. Instead of the usual compiled together single binary Go application, we are going to separate the two. Why? Because usually a React frontend is just a &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; SPA app with very little requirements in terms of resources, while the Go backend does most of the leg work, requiring a lot more resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Kubernetes based Cluster for Various Services with auto HTTPS - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/15/kubernetes-cluster-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/15/kubernetes-cluster-part2/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
This is a continuation of the previous post about my Kubernetes infrastructure located here. The two remaining points are to deploy Athens Go proxy and setting up monitoring.
Athens Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Athens.
First of all if you are a helm user, Athens has an awesome set of helm charts which you can use to deploy it in your cluster. Located here.
I prefer to deploy my own config files, but that&amp;rsquo;s me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I killed my entire Kubernetes cluster</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/01/killing-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/01/killing-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Intro One morning I woke up and tried to access my gitea just to find that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t running.
I checked my cluster and found that the whole thing was dead as meat. I quickly jumped in and ran k get pods -A to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on. None of my services worked.
What immediately struck my eye was a 100+ pods of my fork_updater cronjob. The fork_updater cronjob which runs once a month, looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Kubernetes based Cluster for Various Services with auto HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/21/kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/21/kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Today, I would like to show you how my infrastructure is deployed and managed. Spoiler alert, I&amp;rsquo;m using Kubernetes to do that.
I know&amp;hellip; What a twist!
Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.
What What services am I running exactly? Here is a list I&amp;rsquo;m running at the time of this writing:
 Athens Go Proxy Gitea The Lounge (IRC bouncer) Two CronJobs  Fork Updater IDLE RPG online checker   My WebSite (gergelybrautigam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Face-recog architecture drawing</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/19/updated-face-recog-drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/19/updated-face-recog-drawing/</guid>
      <description>I had a lot of fun using Procreate to re-draw the architecture image I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn for my distribute face recognition application detailed in this post Distributed Face-Recognition App.
Without much fanfare, here is the drawing:
Thanks, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes distributed application deployment with sample Face Recognition App</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/03/15/kubernetes-distributed-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 23:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/03/15/kubernetes-distributed-application/</guid>
      <description>Intro Alright folks. Settle in and get comfortable. This is going to be a long, but hopefully, fun ride.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to deploy a distributed application with Kubernetes. I attempted to create an application that I thought resembled a real world app. Obviously I had to cut some corners due to time and energy constraints.
My focus will be on Kubernetes and deployment.
Shall we delve right in?
The Application TL;DR The application itself consists of six parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes distributed application deployment with sample Face Recognition App</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/03/15/kubernetes-distributed-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 23:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/03/15/kubernetes-distributed-application/</guid>
      <description>Intro Alright folks. Settle in and get comfortable. This is going to be a long, but hopefully, fun ride.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to deploy a distributed application with Kubernetes. I attempted to create an application that I thought resembled a real world app. Obviously I had to cut some corners due to time and energy constraints.
My focus will be on Kubernetes and deployment.
Shall we delve right in?
The Application TL;DR The application itself consists of six parts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
