<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>notetaking on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/notetaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notetaking on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 01:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/notetaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I track tasks with Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2024/09/17/how-i-track-tasks-with-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2024/09/17/how-i-track-tasks-with-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>How I track tasks with Obsidian Hello. This will be a run-down on how I track tasks and projects and long-term things, like reading a book, tracking a project or traveling using the PARA method.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it!
Task tracking queue The way I track tasks is through a queuing system. To not get overloaded by tasks, I just simply put the next task into the queue and take out the top recent if I&amp;rsquo;m done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital and Analog notes together</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/07/28/digital-and-analog-notes-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/07/28/digital-and-analog-notes-together/</guid>
      <description>Digital and analog notes together This fight is as old as time itself. Okay, maybe not that old. But as soon as viable digital note-taking tools appeared it was on. Since then, many solutions that live together have appeared. PKM tools like Second Brain running hand-in-hand with Zettelkasten or BuJo have opened my eyes to combining them in a way that makes the outcome more powerful than each alone would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming the habit of analog journaling - Why the digital format did not work for me</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/01/04/forming-the-habit-of-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/01/04/forming-the-habit-of-journaling/</guid>
      <description>You can see, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to decide on a title. That&amp;rsquo;s because I wanted to express more than a &amp;ldquo;How to get started with Journaling&amp;rdquo; kind of vibe. There are a lot of posts about that already. Rather, this post depicts my struggle to get into this habit.
TL;DR
It turned out that it took way too long to get into writing a simple entry with too many steps. Taking out a notebook and starting to write is a lot faster and cheaper.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
