<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Play Framwork on Ramblings of a build engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/tags/play-framwork/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Play Framwork on Ramblings of a build engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/tags/play-framwork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning programming with a visual mind</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/09/learning-programming-with-a-visual-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/09/learning-programming-with-a-visual-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to write to you about &lt;strong&gt;learning&lt;/strong&gt; something with a &lt;strong&gt;visual mind&lt;/strong&gt;. There are a gazillion posts out there that tell you how to learn something with a visual mind. However, there are only a few &lt;strong&gt;actually describing&lt;/strong&gt; how to learn something as complicated and logical as programming. How do you draw up a function? How do you draw up a cycle or a structure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually these are really &lt;strong&gt;easy&lt;/strong&gt;. A &lt;strong&gt;cycle&lt;/strong&gt;? No problem. What&amp;#8217;s a &lt;strong&gt;circle&lt;/strong&gt; if not a cycle? &lt;strong&gt;Structure&lt;/strong&gt;? This should be an easy one. You can draw a whole &lt;strong&gt;building&lt;/strong&gt; and then place &lt;strong&gt;building blocks&lt;/strong&gt; into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a very &lt;strong&gt;strong visual mind&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;#8217;t remember names good for example however I remember every and each &lt;strong&gt;face very distinct&lt;/strong&gt;. So if you come up to me, don&amp;#8217;t be surprised if I don&amp;#8217;t remember your name. So as I grew older and I took learning into my own hand I realised that there are &lt;strong&gt;techniques&lt;/strong&gt; out there that I could have used to &lt;strong&gt;boost my learning&lt;/strong&gt; in the early stages of my life too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is no such thing as to be late for something. &lt;strong&gt;Life is constant learning&lt;/strong&gt;. So don&amp;#8217;t hesitate to start learning something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;started&lt;/strong&gt; to learn &lt;strong&gt;Scala&lt;/strong&gt; for example and I was &lt;strong&gt;brainstorming&lt;/strong&gt; as how to &lt;strong&gt;draw&lt;/strong&gt; up a good map for some programming practices. &lt;strong&gt;Brainstorming&lt;/strong&gt; can help you coming up with something that can &lt;strong&gt;display your idea&lt;/strong&gt;. Try to brainstorm &lt;strong&gt;in words only&lt;/strong&gt; rather then sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I came up with these two for now, with the &lt;strong&gt;play framework&lt;/strong&gt; in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dl.dropbox.com/u/7604030/structure.png&#34; alt=&#34;Structure&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![Route][2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some of you &lt;strong&gt;might say&lt;/strong&gt; this &lt;strong&gt;took long&lt;/strong&gt; and is &lt;strong&gt;unnecessary&lt;/strong&gt;. The information displayed can be &lt;strong&gt;remembered easily&lt;/strong&gt; and that these drawings took longer then writing up two or three words. Now let&amp;#8217;s see&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These drawing, which are really &lt;strong&gt;rough&lt;/strong&gt; actually, took me about &lt;strong&gt;10 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; while reading and learning and what not. Yes they take longer. But if I write down &lt;strong&gt;two words&lt;/strong&gt; how long will I remember them? I already &lt;strong&gt;forgot after I wrote it down&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This drawing with the griffon legs? &lt;strong&gt;Stuck there forever&lt;/strong&gt;. ( Don&amp;#8217;t ask about the legs.. don&amp;#8217;t know where they came from&amp;#8230; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So visualisation goes a long way in your brain if you are wired that way. Remember that there is NOTHING that you can&amp;#8217;t display with a little bit of creativity and graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohh and btw&amp;#8230; Chances are that you only read the words in &lt;strong&gt;BOLD&lt;/strong&gt; because your mind draws your attention to parts that stand out. And also you want to get over reading this article fast and you appreciate if key elements are taken out for you without the unimportant gibberish in between. 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dl.dropbox.com/u/7604030/route.jpg&#34;&gt;http://dl.dropbox.com/u/7604030/route.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>