<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cucumber-jvm on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/tags/cucumber-jvm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cucumber-jvm on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/tags/cucumber-jvm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber Test Name and Tags on Feature</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/15/cucumber-test-name-and-tags-on-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/15/cucumber-test-name-and-tags-on-feature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to show you a gem today that I found out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently there is no easy way to get to the name of an executing cucumber scenario in cucumber-jvm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try something like that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that isn’t giving you too much now is it? And the API of scenario is as small as it can get. It offers you four options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ember&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;getStatus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;isFailed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t help me. I wanted to get the name of the executed feature and the tags on that particular feature. I thought that’s got to be as easy as just getting a scenario accessing the feature and get the tags. Hooooowww boy I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up with this….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohhhhh yes! The fields which I wanted were all private and not accessible. I’m sure there was a reason behind this decision but if it was sensible it eludes me. But in the world of programming nothing is impossible they say so there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cucumberFeature there will be everything what you need. Tags, Names, Tests, Execution time. Everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that cucumber runs with jUnit so if there is a better way to do this please for the love of my sanity share it with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as always,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
