<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minecraft on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/minecraft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Minecraft on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/minecraft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft world automatic backup to AWS S3 bucket - Part 2 (Custom functions)</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/17/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/17/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got an update for the backup script. This time, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the ability to implement your own upload capabilities. I provide a mock implementation for the required functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the script again, now modified and a bit cleaned up. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft world automatic backup to AWS S3 bucket</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/16/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/16/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
Previously we created a Minecraft server using Docker. After my server got popular in the family, and a lot of stuff started to pile up on it, as a good IT person, I&amp;rsquo;m backing up the world once in a while.
For that, I&amp;rsquo;m using AWS S3 with the CLI and a little bash script which runs once a week.
The script is really straightforward. I&amp;rsquo;m doing manual versioning, although S3 does provide one out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Server with Docker on OSX &#43; Mods</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/29/minecraft-server-with-docker-and-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/29/minecraft-server-with-docker-and-osx/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
Intro Today, I wanted to write about how to create a secure server in a container. Ideally, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to run your server on your own machine. Running it in a container gives you a much needed control and an extra layer of security.
Docker On OSX While on a mac, you have a couple of options to run docker.
Docker-Machine Docker-Machine
Docker machine is very simple. It just creates a Linux vm in the background on the given driver, for us it will be VirtualBox.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
