<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 01:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-04</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/04/21/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/04/21/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;readers-digest&#34;&gt;Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly
basis. Here is April of 2021 so far. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;invincible&#34;&gt;Invincible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing it air on Amazon Prime, I had to go and read the comic. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a lot, but I assure you it&amp;rsquo;s worth it.
Some spoiler alerts&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so we follow this guy, Mark Grayson. He&amp;rsquo;s Invincible. He is also and alien, called a Viltrumite. I can hardly
summaries over 3000 pages of comic books so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to be brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Viltrumites are a race of warrior people who wants to conquer the whole galaxy. They also have the power to do so.
They are virtually immortal, live for thousands of years and are very durable. They can fly, have super strength and
a bunch of other things. The stories are insane. We follow all kinds of people across multiverses, a lot of villains and
heroes. There is gore, sex, violance and immature jokes all around. It&amp;rsquo;s fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are better episodes and there are boring episodes as it goes with these things. The one thing that bothered me a lot
is that the Viltrumites, of course, have a weak spot. You have to remember that these are people who want to be eliminated
by a lot of other people in the whole galaxy. There is a literal coalition of planets who want to kill them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there are two main things which can kill / incapacitate them. The first one is a virus, which was developed by a
traiter Viltrumite which killed like 99.9% of them. And the other is the same weakness as the things have in the movie
called The quiet place. It&amp;rsquo;s specific frequency sound. Granted, some very specific frequency, but it&amp;rsquo;s sound. Because Viltrumites have a
delicate equilibrium because of their flying ability, if there is a specific frequency sound being emitted in close proximity
it can incapacitate or even kill a Viltrumite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which makes me wonder that for thousands of years in multiple, parallel universes and with thousands of alien races,
nobody even thought of doing that? It had to be Earth and Humans ( and a Dinosaur ) who came up with it? That&amp;rsquo;s just
implausible really. And after being used only a couple of times, they don&amp;rsquo;t use it again on a global scale!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways. The story is still incredible and it has a lot of amazing content so I encourage comic lovers to read it all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month. Some lengthy blog posts and Invincible pretty much took up my reading time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as always,
Thanks for reading,
Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-03</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/03/23/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/03/23/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;readers-digest&#34;&gt;Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly
basis. Here is March of 2021 so far. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-aurora-database-paper&#34;&gt;The Aurora Database paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper about Aurora database from AWS can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://nil.csail.mit.edu/6.824/2020/papers/aurora.pdf&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;.
It details the design decision taken to support a highly available, fault tolerant, fast replicating
database. They take the following approach&amp;hellip; They modified mysql database such as that they only send
around the redo log and the redo log is enough to recover / replicate in order to achieve write and
read consistency. They separate the data into Protected Groups and speed up terabytes of recovery by
doing 10 Gigabyte segments in parallel. The database IS the logs. By only replicating the log instead
of the data and the data page, they save millions in networks costs. The main gain however, is that
the storage was modified to understand the application. Instead of using General store they use a storage
which understand the data. In this case, decoupling storage from the database, as so many do, was actually
a drawback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gcatch-paper&#34;&gt;GCatch paper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper is a static concurrency bug analyser for Go found here &lt;a href=&#34;https://songlh.github.io/paper/gcatch.pdf&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ingenious! It&amp;rsquo;s a static analyser which finds mostly blocking bugs using channels in Go. In Go, it&amp;rsquo;s
really easy to write concurrent software using something called &lt;a href=&#34;https://tour.golang.org/concurrency/2&#34;&gt;Channels&lt;/a&gt;.
They are basically coroutines multiplexed onto kernel threads and thus you can have a million of them
running around doing stuff. Go effectively made IO operators CPU bound with them. Coroutines aren&amp;rsquo;t new,
however, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to mess up code with channels in subtle ways. Analyzers exist, however, GCatch
argues that they can&amp;rsquo;t find the most subtle of bugs, only some surface bugs really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes a tool which does inter-procedural, path-sensitive analysis and uses Z3 to find paths
which can lead to deadlocks in code that uses locking primitives and channels. It also contains five other
prominent tools. It converts mutexes into channels internally with buffer size zero and sends on it on
Lock and reads from it on Unlock, then performs a bunch of path combinations and goes through those
suspicious paths and performs its analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They found a hundred and something bugs in Docker and Kubernetes. Things like, sending on a channel in
&lt;code&gt;select&lt;/code&gt; when in fact, a timeout already returned, thus that Go routine is not indefinitely stuck. Since
it can&amp;rsquo;t send its output on the channel, the program didn&amp;rsquo;t quit so it&amp;rsquo;s not GC-d. A simple fix is to
make the channel of size 1 so even if there is a chance that the scope quit it can still send and quit.
Like Exec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting read and the tool is awesome, however&amp;hellip;. It was written with Go 14 and it&amp;rsquo;s proving to
be difficult to port to current version using modules. I would hate to see this tool getting left behind
because it can&amp;rsquo;t be turned into a linter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rhythm-of-war---brandon-sanderson&#34;&gt;Rhythm of War - Brandon Sanderson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Rhythm-War-Stormlight-Archive-Book-ebook/dp/B0826NKZHR&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An epic continuation of this saga with over a 1000 pages long and 54 hours of listening time on Audible.
This story has been ongoing for a while now. Brandon Sanderson came out with the first book back in 2010.
This is the continuation of the Stormlight Archive series. These are massive master pieces. I first came
along Brandon Sanderson when I read the Mistborn series. That was another epic novel. I love reading
Sanderson because he comes up with some unique ways of magic or magic like abilities which have some
divine sense in the end, or have some interesting explanation. And their abilities are almost always
used in interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a simple ability to pull or push metal. Turns out that results in things like, shooting
coins, or literally flying as the person tosses a coin to the ground and pushes on it, pushing themselves
upwards in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could write many many pages about each and every fantastic novel, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to stick to this one
expecting that people know about the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this one as I&amp;rsquo;m insane busy, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have read a 1000 something pages book.
The fantastic work of Micheal Kramer and Kate Reading is always a treat to listen too. They are both
excellent readers always making the characters live through their words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SPOILERS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time we mostly follow Eshonai&amp;rsquo;s and Venli&amp;rsquo;s but we finally also get what we wanted all these years.
Finally, Kaladin and Shallan face their inner demons. And even though they aren&amp;rsquo;t fully okay, Kaladin
speaks his fourth oat and Shallan remembers her past. As much as I love this story, I don&amp;rsquo;t believe I
would have been able to listen or read another 1000 pages without these two resolving their problems.
You root for them so hard, it&amp;rsquo;s exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t spoil everything but the twist at the end left me dumbstruck! It was such an amazing finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story follows the fused as they invade Urithiru. There is a side story for Navani and Jasna
doing their own thing and we do root for Navani and her fantastic discoveries regarding light and powers,
but Jasna is a side character in this story. Another main character is Witt. We finally get to know
who he is and where he comes from. We also understand now that the Fused are actually from another planet
in the same system and Odium just wants to get off this system and fight a holy war with some ancient Gods
somewhere. A lot of things which made no sense are revealed finally. I recommend it if you have the time
to listen or read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-take-smart-notes&#34;&gt;How to take smart notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/How-Take-Smart-Notes-Nonfiction-ebook/dp/B06WVYW33Y&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one&amp;rsquo;s review will be condensed because it would be rather lengthy otherwise. It&amp;rsquo;s basically talking about
how to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://zettelkasten.de/&#34;&gt;Zettelkasten&lt;/a&gt; system. But it does so much more then that. It challenges
the way you think, the way you learn the way things are taught in school and the way you process and store
information. Condensed I would say these are the main points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect new information to existing information. Information without connection isn&amp;rsquo;t worth much and will be
remembered poorly or not at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always read with a pen in your hand and take notes about what you are reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always use your own words and never just copy blindly; by doing this, you will better understand what you just
read. The same goes to things like, writing a blog in which you explain something you think you know. It reveals
the black holes in your knowledge which you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t try to group based on topics. That will result in forced connections and will leave you confined within
that topic. Topics should emerge from your notes and then gathered into indexes which contain links to related
notes and information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tags are useful but don&amp;rsquo;t over do them. If you have a 1000 tags your information will be lost and hard to find
because things that are unrelated will show up in the searches. So go easy on the tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note taking is a chore. It&amp;rsquo;s not something that you just do and it just works. Good note taking requires effort.
You take notes while you read then transcribe them into Zettelkasten and throw away the rest. Those are transient
notes. Zettelkasten notes focus on the gist of things. On the meat!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s all for this months. Rhythm of War, the papers and the note taking book pretty much took all my
time away, so not much else got done since January. But I still think this is a nice finish. Especially
considering Rhythm of War was such a huge epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as always,
Thanks for reading,
Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-01</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/02/01/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/02/01/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;readers-digest&#34;&gt;Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly
basis. Here is January of 2021 so far. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-systems-red---murderbot&#34;&gt;All systems red - Murderbot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is SHORT. It&amp;rsquo;s little over 3 hours of listening time. I&amp;rsquo;m listening at 1.30 so it&amp;rsquo;s just short of 2 hours.
But it&amp;rsquo;s entertaining. The murderbot series is following a rouge security bot which hacked its own governor module
and is self aware and free. But&amp;hellip; it kind of hates humans and interacting with them. It just calls itself murderbot
but has no intention of killing all humans. Instead, all its wants to do is basically&amp;hellip; watch movies and various series on something called a Feed. In the first book of the series, this one, we follow Murderbot protect a few humans
that it gets to short of like after an attempt on their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrator, Kevin R. Free, is doing a great job of impersonating the robot and you can feel the anxiety from his words when inevitably, the robot has to interact with humans. Whether it likes it or not&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;artificial-condition---murderbot&#34;&gt;Artificial Condition - Murderbot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another short story following our Murderbot. This time, it wants to get to the bottom of a mystery involving its past.
In his past, the Murderbot, when it hacked its governor module, it went berserk and killed 80 people in the process. The company who owned it, covered it all up. Or so it thought. During its journey to find out what happened it met a new friend, Art. Art is a huge vessel capable of massive computing capacity, and happens to also love watching series.
They team up and help a rag-tag group of researchers while trying to find out what happened to Murderbot and those 80 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rogue-protocol&#34;&gt;Rogue Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fantastic episode of Murderbot. You can sense that the bot is slowly evolving into a more caring bot. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s saying repeatedly that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t case, it starts to care. This book was an action packed one. Lot&amp;rsquo;s of tension and fear inducing moments. Silence then all out war! We also meet Micky, who is a &amp;ldquo;pet bot&amp;rdquo; for some humans. Their relationship starts off as rocky but after a while, Murderbot comes to appreciate Micky for another free soul. There are some open question in there once the story finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vexed-generation---magician-20&#34;&gt;The vexed generation - Magician 2.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer, I followed Magician 2.0 with an interest. I listen to all of the books in the series. It was fun at first, but then started to get a bit low in quality and repetitive. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about the people in it, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about what&amp;rsquo;s happening to them. And since they are effectively immortal there is no real danger to them at all. In this episode however, there was real danger at the end. And while the protagonist kids were kind of annoying, and it could have been narrated better and I felt like some of the characters weren&amp;rsquo;t fully utilized, the story kind of still was fun to read. Definitely better than the previous one about dragons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heavens-river---bobiverse&#34;&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s River - Bobiverse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest addition to the Bobiverse universe. This time there is civil war amongst the Bobs and, of course, there is a new species to explore. The species was interesting, and the talk about mega-structures was also interesting, but I found that the lack of coding, and fighting and technical stuff ( what caught me on the first couple of Bob adventures ) left me wanting for more and left me with an empty feeling at the end. I really missed the proves of Bob and couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less about Starfleet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;armada&#34;&gt;Armada&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was interesting. It talks about the same premise as The Last Starfighter ( there is a reference to that in there ) which I found fascinating as a child. It is about the fact that an alien race uses video games to find the best soldier for a mission to save the universe. This time though the Earth is doing the recruiting and it is against an alien invasion. And much like Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game, it turns out that the threat is real and that all fighting on the video game that our protagonist did was preparing him for this situation. The twist was pretty good too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prometheus-up-and-running&#34;&gt;Prometheus Up And Running&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one has a larger post incoming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for this month.
Thanks for reading,
Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
