<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Ramblings of a build engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Ramblings of a build engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Autodeploy with Wercker and Github - Pages</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/10/hugo-autodeploy-with-wercker</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/10/hugo-autodeploy-with-wercker</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There already is a nice tutorial on how to create github-pages with Hugo &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; if you prefer deplying your pages to a different branch on the same repo. There is also a post about Wercker and Hugo &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/automated-deployments/&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; deploying pages to said separate branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I took an easier approach on the matter with a completely separate branch for my blog source and my compiled github pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog sits here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skarlso/skarlso.github.io&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Skarlso/skarlso.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. In order to deploy to it, I just have to commit a new blog post to this repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Skarlso/blogsource&#34;&gt;Blog Source&lt;/a&gt;. After that, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wercker.com/&#34;&gt;Wercker&lt;/a&gt; takes care of the rest. It builds my blog, and pushes the generated pages to my blog&amp;rsquo;s repository to the master branch without creating the gh-pages branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wercker yml for that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yml&#34;&gt;box: debian
build:
    steps:
        - arjen/hugo-build:
            theme: redlounge
deploy:
    steps:
        - install-packages:
            packages: git ssh-client
        - leipert/git-push:
            gh_oauth: $GIT_TOKEN
            repo: skarlso/skarlso.github.io
            branch: master
            basedir: public
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty easy. The $GIT_TOKEN is a variable set-up on Wercker containing a restricted token which is only good for pushing. And note that you have to use an explicit package name with git-push or else Wercker will not find that step. Hugo-build will build my blog with a simple command using redlounge theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it. No other setup is necessary and no new branch will be made. Any questions, please feel free to leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>