<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>barcoding on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/tags/barcoding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in barcoding on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/tags/barcoding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TDD and Game of Life</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/07/12/tdd-and-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/07/12/tdd-and-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>So today at 8-12PM I had a great session with two friends of mine. It was awesome. Like a mini code retreat.</p>
<p>We set down in a musky bar, drank wine and beer and cider, and decided to practice some TDD with the well known problem of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway's_Game_of_Life" target="_blank">Conway&rsquo;s Game of Life</a>. This challenge is really interesting. I never done it before, ever. So it was a really good practice for me.</p>
<p>So.</p>
<p><strong>In the beginning there was Test</strong></p>
<p>One of my friends and I started out by developing the implementation for the game while the second one was mentoring and couching us. As with any problem I&rsquo;m facing now days, I started with writing a failing test first. I didn&rsquo;t write any kind of production code yet. I wrote a test testing for having the class called game of life.</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt">1
</span><span class="lnt">2
</span><span class="lnt">3
</span><span class="lnt">4
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-java" data-lang="java">    <span class="nd">@Test</span>
    <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kt">void</span> <span class="nf">shouldHaveClassForGameOfLife</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
        <span class="n">GameOfLife</span> <span class="n">gameOfLife</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="n">GameOfLife</span><span class="o">();</span>
    <span class="o">}</span>
</code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div><p>This wasn&rsquo;t compiling of course because I didn&rsquo;t have any kind of GameOfLife class. But intelliJ is so intelligent that I simply pressed Alt+Enter and created the class immediately. The class didn&rsquo;t have anything in it, but I already had a passing test.</p>
<p>So this went on and on and I created one test after another while my other coding friend did the same.</p>
<p><strong>Now the amazing part</strong></p>
<p>I begun working on the Grid. A simple octagonal coordinating system. This was represented in the beginning with a simple two dimensional array with Cells in it.</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt">1
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre class="chroma"><code class="language-java" data-lang="java">    <span class="n">Cells</span><span class="o">[][]</span> <span class="n">cells</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="n">Cells</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="n">50</span><span class="o">][</span><span class="n">50</span><span class="o">];</span>
</code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div><p>This of course wasn&rsquo;t dynamic. I didn&rsquo;t care about that yet. I had my grid of cells. These cells were initially all dead.</p>
<p>Now, the interesting part is that as I developed my Grid finding out the Cells neighbours and counting them, my friend worked on the Cells themselves and getting their next state and killing them based on the rules.</p>
<p>We never talked to each other, didn&rsquo;t agree on roles or directions or anything. And even so at the and. We were at a stage where we met in the middle and could merge our codes! Our little game of life evolved with a push of a button. ( Three actually. )</p>
<p>This was simply amazing. Without ever talking about the direction we want to go we created a working code base that could be merged!</p>
<p><strong>It just works</strong></p>
<p>Before TDD I would have tackled this problem much differently. And it would have taken me much more time too. This was like an hour or so.</p>
<p>TDD helped me break down the job into small, manageable tasks. I created and deleted and rewrote tests as I went on and on and developed the algorithm for my Grid and Cell. And eventually the problem slowly unfolded itself right before my eyes. I began to see the connections. I began to see the beauty. I began to understand! This is something I rarely enjoyed previously without using TDD.</p>
<p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<p>I recommend for you guys to do the same. Just sit down, find a problem, find a coding kata and just do it with TDD. With PROPER TDD.</p>
<p>Here are some good sites for katas and problems:</p>
<p><a href="http://codekata.pragprog.com/" target="_blank"><a href="http://codekata.pragprog.com/">http://codekata.pragprog.com/</a></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.spoj.pl/problems/classical/" target="_blank"><a href="http://www.spoj.pl/problems/classical/">http://www.spoj.pl/problems/classical/</a></a></p>
<p>Just select a problem and then start cracking on it. Do this every time you have some free time. Like a martial art trainee doing basic exercises and you will get better at problem solving and at TDD too. I promise.</p>
<p>Happy coding and good night!</p>
<p>Gergely.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>