<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>journaling on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/journaling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in journaling on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 01:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/journaling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forming the habit of analog journaling - Why the digital format did not work for me</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/01/04/forming-the-habit-of-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/01/04/forming-the-habit-of-journaling/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>You can see, I wasn&rsquo;t able to decide on a title. That&rsquo;s because I wanted to express more than a &ldquo;How to get started
with Journaling&rdquo; kind of vibe. There are a <em>lot</em> of posts about that already. Rather, this post depicts my struggle to get
into this habit.</p>
<p>TL;DR</p>
<p>It turned out that it took way too long to get into writing a simple entry with too many steps. Taking out a notebook
and starting to write is a lot faster and cheaper.</p>
<p>For more details about the hows and whys, dear reader, continue.</p>
<h2 id="digital-note-taking">Digital Note Taking</h2>
<p>Let me tell you right off the bat, that I tried MANY things in the digital area. Wikis, note takers, markdown, not
markdown. Syncs, dedicated software, and lately, Obsidian.</p>
<p><a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian</a> works the best for me to this day. I use it for a lot of things, like notes for when
I&rsquo;m working on an issue. I use it as a second brain to store information. But that&rsquo;s about it. I found it cumbersome
when I wanted to use it for anything more/else. Such as journaling or Zettelkasten even.</p>
<p>As a <a href="https://www.buildingasecondbrain.com/">Second-Brain</a> it is invaluable. I search in it and review it when I can.
But as a means to get into journaling and building a habit, it&rsquo;s not working out. Why you may ask dear reader?</p>
<p>Simple. It takes way too many steps to get to it. Even after I reduced some, it still takes too many steps. In the book,
Atomic Habits, to build a habit, you need four basic steps.</p>
<ul>
<li>Cue</li>
<li>Craving</li>
<li>Response</li>
<li>Reward</li>
</ul>
<p>One of the most important steps is <em>Make a new Habit more accessible/visible/obvious</em>. Obsidian is way too far away.</p>
<p>What are some of the steps to access Obsidian, let&rsquo;s say, in the morning?</p>
<ul>
<li>Wake up</li>
<li>(( do other, none relevant things ))</li>
<li>Walk to the computer</li>
<li>Sit down
( Here is where it will fork around a bit )
(( if, I remembered on the previous day to not turn off my computer but let is sleep ))</li>
<li>Hit a key on the keyboard to let it wake up</li>
<li>Wait for my monitor to spin up</li>
<li>Hit a couple more keys and get impatient in waiting</li>
<li>The monitor finally turns on</li>
<li>Log in
(( if, I turned my computer off because I don&rsquo;t want it to run all day then night ))</li>
<li>Turn on the computer</li>
<li>Wait of encryption to unlock</li>
<li>The rest from above
(( if, I remembered on the previous day to leave Obsidian open as the forefront app ))</li>
<li>Once the computer is unlocked, create a new note</li>
<li>Format it, add some title, start writing ( done )
(( if, I didn&rsquo;t ))</li>
<li>Switch to / Open Obsidian</li>
<li>Create a new note</li>
<li>Format it, add some title, start writing ( done )
(( if, I left a new entry already open ( this is a <em>HUGE</em> if ) and Obsidian is in focus ))</li>
<li>Start writing</li>
</ul>
<p>So, even if I develop the habit to prepare for the next time ( which is also a thing in Atomic Habits ) I would have to
remember a lot to do for it to work perfectly. And <em>even then</em> I would have to wait for all the things to turn on.</p>
<p>This is just too much time. Second Brain works, because I&rsquo;m already at my computer when I&rsquo;m learning something/do some
kind of research/working. If I&rsquo;m not at my computer, I probably have my phone with me, on which I can type rather
quickly. So&hellip; why not just use that, you might ask, dear reader?</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s investigate.</p>
<ul>
<li>Wake up</li>
<li>Get my phone</li>
<li>Unlock with pin ( I hate any kind of recognition thing that lets people unlock my phone with my unconscious body )</li>
<li>Open the app ( I put it in an easily accessible location )</li>
<li>Click / Switch / Swipe through it to open a new note ( or press a button that immediately opens a new note )</li>
<li>Start typing</li>
</ul>
<p>This is <em>almost</em> reasonable. But turns out, I hate having to type in my pin, select the app then press another thing.
It&rsquo;s just too high of an entry point. Maybe if my habit would already be formed the urge to do the thing I wanted would
be higher. However&hellip; There is another aspect to it that many will not acknowledge or glance over rather quickly.</p>
<h3 id="the-sense-of-not-being-present">The sense of not being present</h3>
<p>Maybe it is just me, but I think it&rsquo;s just plain rude if you aren&rsquo;t living alone. If you have family, and your
relationship is good, you would like to engage with them and not bury yourself behind a screen, or immediately sit down
in front of the computer. Of course, I can explain to my wife that I&rsquo;m just journaling or writing down something, but
for me, it still feels rude. I can&rsquo;t help it.</p>
<p>In contrast, when I sit down and write something in a notebook that&rsquo;s a conversation starter. My 5-year-old daughter
immediately gets engaged and asks, what are you writing daddy? If I would be buried in the phone screen she&rsquo;ll probably
nag that I&rsquo;m not paying attention to her. And, I believe, she would be right in that nag. Therefore, I try to avoid
checking my phone too often when I&rsquo;m around my family. But maybe, that&rsquo;s just me.</p>
<p>If you aren&rsquo;t convinced yet, here is another story. Recently, I had to go to a doctor because my knees are busted and
need sugary. I write down everything in a small notebook when I feel the need, but this time, I forgot to take it
with me, because I was using a different bag.</p>
<p>Thus, I resorted to taking notes and writing down some questions on my phone. The doctor actually got annoyed with me
after two seconds, because she thought I&rsquo;m not paying attention at all. Since it just looked like I was playing with my phone.
I explained that, oh, no, no, I&rsquo;m just taking notes and I have some questions written down here I would like to ask.</p>
<p>She said something like, oh okay, and proceeded to answer, but after a minute or two, she asked me to put it away,
because it was annoying. And I completely understood. I never got any side-eye because I was taking notes in my notebook.
Even in today&rsquo;s world, people don&rsquo;t associate a phone with notes. They associate the phone with playing around. There is
a reason why many schools just plain don&rsquo;t allow the usage of phones in the classroom. Even if you are just taking it to
take notes, a notification could pop up, or you could get distracted by other apps on your phone. That&rsquo;s just the nature
of the beast.</p>
<h2 id="analog-note-taking">Analog Note Taking</h2>
<p>Let&rsquo;s take a stab at analog note-taking now. I think, dear reader, you already read a bunch of things about the benefits
of analog note-taking. Hand-eye coordination. Easy to draw, scribble, and be more specific with diagrams, boxes, whatever.
Even if you take notes on an iPad, it&rsquo;s not the same and you know it. Remarkable might work for some, but not all. And
it&rsquo;s expensive to be a pen and paper that you have to charge. Also, today&rsquo;s notebooks are mostly recycled paper. And if
you still aren&rsquo;t convinced, you can buy the ones which explicitly say, they will contribute to the planet&rsquo;s health.</p>
<p>We also know the drawbacks. Let&rsquo;s take a look.</p>
<h3 id="unsearchable">Unsearchable</h3>
<p>Indeed, a paper can&rsquo;t have a neat little search engine in it. There is the Second Brain for that sort of information.
That said, it can be helped a little bit. Try looking at indexing methods for the written word.
I like <a href="https://thetechnicalgeekery.com/2013/06/the-complete-guide-to-indexing-your-paper-notes/">this</a>](<a href="https://thetechnicalgeekery.com/2013/06/the-complete-guide-to-indexing-your-paper-notes/">https://thetechnicalgeekery.com/2013/06/the-complete-guide-to-indexing-your-paper-notes/</a>) detailed post about indexing and indexing techniques from Soren Bjornstad.</p>
<p>Whether you index by page or by keywords it gets a lot better finding things in your notebooks than flipping around
pages.</p>
<h3 id="too-much-space">Too much space</h3>
<p>After a couple of years of doing this, I would imagine, that there will be several notebooks stored somewhere under your
desk or in a drawer. I recommend reading <a href="https://austinkleon.com/2021/05/20/indexing-filing-systems-and-the-art-of-finding-what-you-have/">this</a> post from Austin Kleon about how to store and index notebooks.</p>
<p>TL;DR: Label them and have a global index that keeps track of some other indexes in all of the books together. It&rsquo;s
not hard setting it up. Austin has a lot of other great posts about that.</p>
<h3 id="crumbles-after-a-couple-hundred-years">Crumbles after a couple hundred years</h3>
<p>Come on.</p>
<h3 id="so-why-does-this-work">So, why does this work?</h3>
<p>Back to the gist of things after this small detour. How <em>did</em> analog note-taking work for me in the end, you might ask
dear reader? Quit talking around circles and show us the meat!</p>
<p>Okay, so, compared to the previous activation cost, let&rsquo;s see what it takes to get started with a notebook.</p>
<ul>
<li>Wake up</li>
<li>(( do other none relevant things ))</li>
<li>Go to my desk</li>
<li>Open my notebook at the last entry ( I have a notebook with a place marker )</li>
<li>Take the pen next to it</li>
<li>Start writing</li>
</ul>
<p>That&rsquo;s it. There are no extra steps whatsoever. The only thing I could make to make this even faster is if it would be
next to my bed. But I prefer to write on a desk in relative comfort.</p>
<p>I found myself looking forward to writing within a week of doing this. After a couple of other weeks, I found
myself re-reading my journal. Something that I have <em>never</em> done with my digital notes.</p>
<p>I went all out, and I keep track of expenses and projects in a project notebook and a small notebook for the
expenses. It works. Why? Because it&rsquo;s visible. It&rsquo;s immediate. It&rsquo;s next to me. I see it all the time. It&rsquo;s not hidden
in an app, not hidden in my computer. It. Is. Right. There.</p>
<p>It turns out, that helps <em>immensely</em> in getting started and building up my habit. I also found myself writing
more and more by hand for other things too. For example, I finished <a href="https://adventofcode.com">Advent Of Code</a> 2022 by
writing everything down. It helped a lot. Something about writing and drawing small diagrams helped a lot in
understanding the problem. I tried doing that digitally one day. I reverted to paper after a few minutes because
it was too cumbersome to create diagrams and map out simple relationships. It&rsquo;s not impossible, but honestly, you will
never replace a simple stroke of a pen with digital technology that doesn&rsquo;t use a&hellip; <em>pen</em>.</p>
<h2 id="just-a-preference">Just a preference?</h2>
<p>So, there you have it, dear reader. That&rsquo;s my preference. You read my story, you know what <em>I</em> like and how <em>I</em> learned
to get into journaling. Maybe this will help you get started a bit and after the habit is strong, you can try and make
it digital. For, I believe, it will never replace my notebook. It&rsquo;s just way too convenient. I can simply start
writing, and drawing, with no battery, no nothing other than the pen drying out or the pages running out.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Thank you for following me on this journey. I hope you enjoyed it.</p>
<p>Have a nice day!</p>
<p>Gergely.</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>