<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 01:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to add a self-signer certificate the GitHub action runner</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/07/04/how-to-add-self-signed-certificates-to-github-action-runner-using-mkcert/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/07/04/how-to-add-self-signed-certificates-to-github-action-runner-using-mkcert/</guid>
      <description>Adding a certificate to a GitHub runner Imagine having a project where you have a server that you would like to run with TLS. Let&amp;rsquo;s say, you want to run a Docker registry in a cluster using TLS. You need the generated certificate&amp;rsquo;s root certificate in the trust store of the GitHub action runner.
This is simple with mkcert.
The action is simple:
name: tests on: pull_request: paths-ignore: - &amp;#39;CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&amp;#39; - &amp;#39;README.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments are back</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/05/11/comments-are-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 02:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/05/11/comments-are-back/</guid>
      <description>Well, the previous post was a lie ( or rather a copy and paste error ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test comments</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/05/11/test-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/05/11/test-comments/</guid>
      <description>Hello dear reader.
I switched to a new theme that has Dark Mode. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping nothing changed regarding the RSS functionality.
I removed the comments because I rarely used them.
Also disabled any sort of tracking.
Enjoy, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark mode and a new theme</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/05/10/dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/05/10/dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>Hello dear reader.
I switched to a new theme that has Dark Mode. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping nothing changed regarding the RSS functionality.
I removed the comments because I rarely used them.
Also disabled any sort of tracking.
Enjoy, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Painless controller testing with e2e-framework and tilt</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/03/12/painless-controller-testing-with-e2e-framework-tilt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/03/12/painless-controller-testing-with-e2e-framework-tilt/</guid>
      <description>Welcome dear reader.
When last we met, we talked a lot about setting up Tilt for rapid controller development.
Now, let&amp;rsquo;s see how powerful Tilt can be once we bring it together with Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; e2e-framework.
Controller E2E Framework I&amp;rsquo;d like to present my controller-e2e-framework which brings Tilt and e2e-framework together to easily write and run tests for controllers that work together.
This framework can be used to integration test or e2e test controllers that work together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Kubernetes Controller Development with Tilt</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/02/25/rapid-controller-development-with-tilt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/02/25/rapid-controller-development-with-tilt/</guid>
      <description>Welcome dear reader.
Today, we are going to dive into how to use Tilt to speed up the feedback loop of developing a Kubernetes controller. We are going to do that using an open-source project called OCM which has a controller called ocm-controller. I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk through the following process:
researching tilt what it could do for me understanding the Tilt file trivial mapping of the developer process understanding Starlark adding more features tackling hot swapping troubleshooting Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forming the habit of analog journaling - Why the digital format did not work for me</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/01/04/forming-the-habit-of-journaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2023/01/04/forming-the-habit-of-journaling/</guid>
      <description>You can see, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to decide on a title. That&amp;rsquo;s because I wanted to express more than a &amp;ldquo;How to get started with Journaling&amp;rdquo; kind of vibe. There are a lot of posts about that already. Rather, this post depicts my struggle to get into this habit.
TL;DR
It turned out that it took way too long to get into writing a simple entry with too many steps. Taking out a notebook and starting to write is a lot faster and cheaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate a sample YAML file from a CRD</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/10/19/crd-to-yaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/10/19/crd-to-yaml/</guid>
      <description>Hello.
This one is a quick update. Just a showcase really.
I wrote a tool to generate a sample YAML file from a CRD.
Given a CRD like this one, it would output a generate yaml sample like this:
apiVersion: infrastructure.cluster.x-k8s.io/v1beta1 kind: AWSCluster metadata: {} spec: additionalTags: {} bastion: allowedCIDRBlocks: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] ami: string disableIngressRules: true enabled: true instanceType: string controlPlaneEndpoint: host: string port: 1 controlPlaneLoadBalancer: additionalSecurityGroups: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] crossZoneLoadBalancing: true healthCheckProtocol: string name: string scheme: string subnets: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] identityRef: kind: AWSCluster name: string imageLookupBaseOS: string imageLookupFormat: string imageLookupOrg: string network: cni: cniIngressRules: - description: string fromPort: 1 protocol: string toPort: 1 securityGroupOverrides: {} subnets: - availabilityZone: string cidrBlock: string id: string ipv6CidrBlock: string isIpv6: true isPublic: true natGatewayId: string routeTableId: string tags: {} vpc: availabilityZoneSelection: string availabilityZoneUsageLimit: 1 cidrBlock: string id: string internetGatewayId: string ipv6: cidrBlock: string egressOnlyInternetGatewayId: string poolId: string tags: {} region: string s3Bucket: controlPlaneIAMInstanceProfile: string name: string nodesIAMInstanceProfiles: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] sshKeyName: string status: bastion: addresses: - address: string type: string availabilityZone: string ebsOptimized: true enaSupport: true iamProfile: string id: string imageId: string instanceState: string networkInterfaces: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] nonRootVolumes: - deviceName: string encrypted: true encryptionKey: string iops: 1 size: 1 throughput: 1 type: string privateIp: string publicIp: string rootVolume: deviceName: string encrypted: true encryptionKey: string iops: 1 size: 1 throughput: 1 type: string securityGroupIds: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] spotMarketOptions: maxPrice: string sshKeyName: string subnetId: string tags: {} tenancy: string type: string userData: string volumeIDs: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] conditions: - lastTransitionTime: string message: string reason: string severity: string status: string type: string failureDomains: {} networkStatus: apiServerElb: attributes: crossZoneLoadBalancing: true idleTimeout: 1 availabilityZones: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] dnsName: string healthChecks: healthyThreshold: 1 interval: 1 target: string timeout: 1 unhealthyThreshold: 1 listeners: - instancePort: 1 instanceProtocol: string port: 1 protocol: string name: string scheme: string securityGroupIds: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] subnetIds: [&amp;#34;string&amp;#34;] tags: {} securityGroups: {} ready: true The link to the repo is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Common Sense guide to Data Structures and Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/09/25/data-structures-and-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/09/25/data-structures-and-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Hello!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on something extensive these days. Like my Grokking Algorithms summary, I now moved on to read Common-Sense Guide to Data Structures and Algorithms.
As with Grokking, I created a Go based repo and added notes for each chapter.
The repo can be located here.
Enjoy, and thanks for reading. Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute to a new repository</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/07/01/how-to-contribute-to-a-new-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/07/01/how-to-contribute-to-a-new-repository/</guid>
      <description>How to contribute to a new repository Hello Dear readers.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through a process of contributing into a new repository. If you are new to Go development and would like to contribute somewhere but are at a loss in large repositories, this post will be for you.
I selected the top repository in trending Go today. Which is istio. I think that&amp;rsquo;s sufficiently large and I have no idea about the repository, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through my process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking on CAPA - The journey of implementing a nontrivial feature in a barely known codebase</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/06/26/hacking-on-capa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/06/26/hacking-on-capa/</guid>
      <description>Hacking on CAPA - The journey of implementing a nontrivial feature in a barely known codebase Hello Dear readers.
Today, I would like to write about a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on these past months or so. This is a longer story and hopefully an interesting one to read.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to write about the journey I took while trying to implement IPv6 based Kubernetes cluster for CAPA and EKS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependabot Bundler</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/05/16/dependabot-bundler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/05/16/dependabot-bundler/</guid>
      <description>Hello Dear readers.
Today, I would like to write about a small pet project of mine called Dependabot Bundler.
We&amp;rsquo;ve all been here:
You would like to review these individually, of course, however, having to individually merge them is quite the pain.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t it a lot better to do this instead?
A lot nicer and more comfortable, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?
This is done by running dependabot-bundler with the following command:
./bundler --token ${GITHUB_TOKEN} --repo eksctl --owner weaveworks --author-name Skarlso --author-email gergely@weave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest - January with Grokking Algorithms Go Generics Repository</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/01/26/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2022/01/26/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>Hello Dear readers.
Today&amp;rsquo;s reader&amp;rsquo;s digest comes with a repo and some code too! Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest - January Immune Immune is an absolutely fabulous book. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing and in time of this pandemic a healthy read to boot. I love biology, but never went too deep into it. This book fascinated me with its colorful images, the style of Kurzgesagt story telling and the man himself, who is the voice of Kurzgesagt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Providers Pattern</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/21/providers-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/21/providers-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Hello Dear readers.
Today, I would like to write about a project design pattern I&amp;rsquo;ve been using successfully over the past years for various projects. It has many variations and it has some design patterns that are commonly found in the wild, so there is nothing really special about it.
Let&amp;rsquo;s begin.
Providers Pattern What is this pattern anyways? It&amp;rsquo;s a pattern I learned while working at ArangoDB. It&amp;rsquo;s quite nice and defines package abstractions wonderfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 12 - Updated</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/17/aoc-day12-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/17/aoc-day12-updated/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 12 - Updated A comment from one of my readers prompted me to revise my solution on this trying to do part 2. The suggestions was that instead of using a struct as seen, use int and keep track of the count for small caves that way. I started to do that but got into various problems along the way when I got frustrated with my code, deleted the whole thing and begun again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 15</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/15/aoc-day15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/15/aoc-day15/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 15 Today, again, we open up Red Blob Games. It is a great source of information and descriptions. Especially, since this scenario is right up Red Blob&amp;rsquo;s ally. We need some weighted path finding. And Red Blob has a lovely post on that using the ever famous Dijkstra algorithm with a Priority Queue.
Day 15 - Part 1 Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it. After refreshing my memory about priority queues, I remembered that there is a package and some sample code in Go which implements priority queues using the container/heap package here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 14</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/14/aoc-day14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/14/aoc-day14/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 14 Now we have to do some chemistry. Santa is pretty cool this way. They have a lot of skills mastered and read manuals like an expert. But this also means that manuals are always faulty. But Santa manages to work around these problems rather well.
Day 14 - Part 1 So, by reading the description and looking at the outcome, that a string only after 5 iterations will be this big, begs the question if we should build a primitive solution for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 13</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/13/aoc-day13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/13/aoc-day13/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 13 This one was a lot of fun! Matrix folding was a bit fiddly but nothing too serious&amp;hellip;
Day13 - Part 1 By solving this part, I actually solved both parts. I had to butcher it to not solve both parts because I already dealt with folding both ways. First, we parse our input.
We read out both the folding and the numbers first for easy handling later:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 12</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/12/aoc-day12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/12/aoc-day12/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 12 EDIT: I revisited this problem and completely revised my solution to it: Day 12 Updated
This one is a bit different from our little BFS walk the other day. I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite remember how DFS works, so I looked at the Wikipedia a bit. Then I remembered that I implemented this previously at some point in a later year.
Disclaimer: I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish part 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 11</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/11/aoc-day11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/11/aoc-day11/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 11 Today was an easier one again. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last did some recursion anyway. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s how I solved this. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure my solution isn&amp;rsquo;t the most efficient one, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s working and it&amp;rsquo;s not horrible.
Day 11 - Part 1 We have some number tracking to do again. This time, instead of fishes, we find ourself an bioluminescent octopus!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 10</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/10/aoc-day10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/10/aoc-day10/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 10 Again, a bit of breathing time with an easier one. Although, it can be difficult, if you go down the path of trying to do it via recursion.
Day 10 - Part 1 We have to match brackets. There can be a bit of a hassle if you go off on the wrong foot and try to implement it using recursion. But that works perfectly fine as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 9</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/09/aoc-day9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/09/aoc-day9/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 9 This one was an interesting one, and a step up from previous days. I used a BFS here and I have a fantastic link for the description, usage and appliance of BFS and others like A*. Pop over to Red Blog Games for all the good stuff. There are fantastic articles about all sorts of path finding and walking algorithms.
Day 9 - Part 1 We start off again with something easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 8</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/08/aoc-day8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/08/aoc-day8/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 8 If yesterday was a bit of a respite from adventuring, today was the boss fight for which we geared up for. The wall of text that hit us in the face, nearly depleted all of our HP. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope tomorrow brings some potions.
Day 8 - Part 1 We start off relatively easy&amp;hellip; We have to deal with old school number displays that use segments to display numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 7</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/07/aoc-day7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/07/aoc-day7/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 7 Day 7 - Part 1 Today we got a bit of respite with an easy one. Sort of like a Dark Souls bonfire.
Let&amp;rsquo;s list our constraints.
Today, we face a giant whale and some crabs in submarines which are less than effective. If they only move horizontally I have no idea how they&amp;rsquo;ve gotten as far as you. Maybe they pivot from time to time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 6</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/06/aoc-day6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/06/aoc-day6/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 6 Alright. This time, we are going to learn something that AOC does from time to time&amp;hellip; Let&amp;rsquo;s break it down.
Day 6 - Part 1 We start off really easy. We venture around in the sea, looking for nothing but trouble. We have our squid friend with us, whom we were telling everything about vents on the sea floor. Which happen to line up perfectly straight for some weird reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 5</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/05/aoc-day5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/05/aoc-day5/</guid>
      <description>Advent of Code - Day 5 Alright. Today, we are going to learn something that will be useful to us in the coming days.
Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we are dealing with.
Edit: An interesting algorithm to read up on is Bresenham&amp;rsquo;s line algorithm.
Day 5 - Part 1 We deal with vents today. The sea is a dangerous place after all. Fortunately for us, these vents line up perfectly so Santa can dodge them easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/04/aoc-day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/04/aoc-day4/</guid>
      <description>Advent of Code - Day 4 Disclaimer: There is surely a better solution than this one. But I&amp;rsquo;m fairly okay with this one. And I wrote it, so&amp;hellip;
Okay, this day was a bit more complex now. But not in understanding what needed to be done, but implementing it. And then, part two of course.
Day 4 - Part 1 We met a squid this day and decided to play a round of Bingo with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/03/aoc-day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/03/aoc-day3/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 3 Here we go for day 3!
This day was a tiny bit more complex. A lot of more things to read for sure! But all the more exciting!
Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it!
Day 3 - Part 1 We are dealing with binary numbers. At fist glance it can be daunting, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually not that complicated. We have to find two numbers. gamma rate and epsilon rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/02/aoc-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/02/aoc-day2/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 2 Here we go for day 2!
These first couple of problems prepare you on how to deal with input mainly. Learn and get used to parsing lines, and get comfortable with data structures.
Day 2 - Part 1 We continue the story of Santa and the submarine. This time, he has the task of trying to steer the thing. The task is straightforward. You get a couple of instructions and based on a value you increase or decrease a positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent Of Code - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/01/aoc-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/12/01/aoc-day1/</guid>
      <description>Advent Of Code - Day 1 Since 2015, Advent Of Code has been a part of my life. I&amp;rsquo;ve done various posts on it already, but this year will be different. I&amp;rsquo;m going to blog every day every solution, why and how I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to that solution.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be ever December, because I&amp;rsquo;m usually unable to solve a problem on a single day in the later days from day 10 or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Programmer&#39;s Brain</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/11/27/summary-of-programmers-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/11/27/summary-of-programmers-brain/</guid>
      <description>Prologue Hello all.
This is a summary of the book Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Brain. Let me begin by saying the book is fantastic and you should definitely read it. The research put into it is phenomenal, and the many linked notes, data and reference make for an amazing and compelling read!
Not to mention that it is fantastic that someone put actual effort and data into finding out how programmers operate, think and behave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-07</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/07/31/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/07/31/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly basis. Here is July of 2021 so far. Enjoy.
Ultimate Go This book is a culmination of Bill Kennedy&amp;rsquo;s Ultimate Go course and notes which were spawned from them by Hoanh An. Bill Kennedy set out to put everything together and create a notebook which can be read and followed like the personal notes of a student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-06</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/06/30/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/06/30/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly basis. Here is June of 2021 so far. Enjoy.
Hell Divers 6: Allegiance I love the Hell Divers series. I listened to this one on audible as always and it was fantastic, as always. King Xavier Rodriguez. That sounds as bad ass as it is. We follow King Xavier and Rhino, his trusted subordinate into battle with a new threat called Skin Walkers and of course the machines, the defectors which are trying to kill everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog refactor</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/05/25/blog-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/05/25/blog-refactor/</guid>
      <description>Blog Refactor Finally, I went back and fixed a lot of old posts and old code entries. I tried to fix and repair links and images, but some are lost forever on some obscure WordPress blog which I used to use.
I&amp;rsquo;m glad though that the code is intact and I could re-read a lot of my old stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how much I evolved, how much my writing evolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-04</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/04/21/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/04/21/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly basis. Here is April of 2021 so far. Enjoy.
Invincible After seeing it air on Amazon Prime, I had to go and read the comic. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a lot, but I assure you it&amp;rsquo;s worth it. Some spoiler alerts&amp;hellip;
Okay, so we follow this guy, Mark Grayson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-03</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/03/23/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/03/23/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly basis. Here is March of 2021 so far. Enjoy.
The Aurora Database paper The paper about Aurora database from AWS can be found here: Paper. It details the design decision taken to support a highly available, fault tolerant, fast replicating database. They take the following approach&amp;hellip; They modified mysql database such as that they only send around the redo log and the redo log is enough to recover / replicate in order to achieve write and read consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reader&#39;s Digest 2021-01</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/02/01/readers-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2021/02/01/readers-digest/</guid>
      <description>Reader&amp;rsquo;s Digest I thought it would a cool idea if I kept a summary of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or listened to on a monthly basis. Here is January of 2021 so far. Enjoy.
All systems red - Murderbot This book is SHORT. It&amp;rsquo;s little over 3 hours of listening time. I&amp;rsquo;m listening at 1.30 so it&amp;rsquo;s just short of 2 hours. But it&amp;rsquo;s entertaining. The murderbot series is following a rouge security bot which hacked its own governor module and is self aware and free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy a Go (Golang) backend with a React frontend separately on Kubernetes - Part One</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/07/23/kubernetes-deploy-golang-react-apps-separately-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/07/23/kubernetes-deploy-golang-react-apps-separately-part1/</guid>
      <description>Intro Welcome. This is a longer post about how to deploy a Go backend with a React frontend on Kubernetes as separate entities. Instead of the usual compiled together single binary Go application, we are going to separate the two. Why? Because usually a React frontend is just a &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; SPA app with very little requirements in terms of resources, while the Go backend does most of the leg work, requiring a lot more resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do a good code review</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/05/11/good-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/05/11/good-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
This time, I would like to talk a little bit about code reviews.
How do you do code reviews? Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to share it in the comments.
How do I do code reviews? Well read on if you would like to know.
The Top Down approach If I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with a small code change, a couple of lines here and there in the odd file first, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to understand why the review is there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make SPA refresh work with a Go backend</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/02/17/making-spa-refresh-work-with-go-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2020/02/17/making-spa-refresh-work-with-go-backend/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Today I would like to share a quick &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; for a problem I&amp;rsquo;ve seen popping up here and there.
That is, if you have a react frontend which is a SPA app but you still want refresh to work. What do I mean by that? Consider the following&amp;hellip;
The problem You have a SPA app with a react router which navigates the user around. The app calls to a backend api which serves content of some kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Kubernetes based Cluster for Various Services with auto HTTPS - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/15/kubernetes-cluster-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/15/kubernetes-cluster-part2/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
This is a continuation of the previous post about my Kubernetes infrastructure located here. The two remaining points are to deploy Athens Go proxy and setting up monitoring.
Athens Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Athens.
First of all if you are a helm user, Athens has an awesome set of helm charts which you can use to deploy it in your cluster. Located here.
I prefer to deploy my own config files, but that&amp;rsquo;s me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Practical Go workshop from Dave Cheney</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/10/practical-go-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/10/practical-go-summary/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
So there is this workshop from Dave Cheney.
And I thought I&amp;rsquo;d draw a sort of summary of that workshop.
Right-click-&amp;gt;Open Image for higher resolution.
Cheers, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I killed my entire Kubernetes cluster</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/01/killing-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/10/01/killing-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Intro One morning I woke up and tried to access my gitea just to find that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t running.
I checked my cluster and found that the whole thing was dead as meat. I quickly jumped in and ran k get pods -A to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on. None of my services worked.
What immediately struck my eye was a 100+ pods of my fork_updater cronjob. The fork_updater cronjob which runs once a month, looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Kubernetes based Cluster for Various Services with auto HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/21/kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/21/kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Today, I would like to show you how my infrastructure is deployed and managed. Spoiler alert, I&amp;rsquo;m using Kubernetes to do that.
I know&amp;hellip; What a twist!
Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.
What What services am I running exactly? Here is a list I&amp;rsquo;m running at the time of this writing:
Athens Go Proxy Gitea The Lounge (IRC bouncer) Two CronJobs Fork Updater IDLE RPG online checker My WebSite (gergelybrautigam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Face-recog architecture drawing</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/19/updated-face-recog-drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/09/19/updated-face-recog-drawing/</guid>
      <description>I had a lot of fun using Procreate to re-draw the architecture image I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn for my distribute face recognition application detailed in this post Distributed Face-Recognition App.
Without much fanfare, here is the drawing:
Thanks, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efferent and Afferent metrics in Go</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/04/21/efferent-and-afferent-metrics-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/04/21/efferent-and-afferent-metrics-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks!
Today I would like to write about a metric that I read in a book called Clean Architecture from Robert Cecil Martin ( Uncle Bob ).
Abstract The metrics I mean are Efferent and Afferent coupling in packages. So you, dear reader, don&amp;rsquo;t have to navigate away from this page, here are the descriptions pasted in:
Afferent couplings (Ca): The number of classes in other packages that depend upon classes within the package is an indicator of the package&amp;rsquo;s responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living with a new Parser for a year</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/04/12/living-with-a-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 08:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/04/12/living-with-a-parser/</guid>
      <description>Living with a Parser</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Hugo Blog Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/03/19/deploy-hugo-blog-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 22:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/03/19/deploy-hugo-blog-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Today I thought I show you how you can use Github Actions to deploy a hugo based blog like this one.
Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
Actions What are actions? If you read the above linked document they are basically steps performed in containers based on some events that happened with your repository. Events can be such as pushing, creating a PR or creating/closing an issue etc.
We need an even on a push.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cronohub: Archive from anywhere to anywhere</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/03/19/cronohub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/03/19/cronohub/</guid>
      <description>Intro Good afternoon folks.
Today, I would like to talk a little bit about Cronohub. It&amp;rsquo;s a Python application which you can use to archive anything from anywhere to anywhere. It uses plugins to archive this versatility.
Let me show you some of its features.
Main Usage Cronohub is a python application which uses the power and ease of usage of Python to give the user a framework. This Framework can then be used to implement concrete functionality in the form of plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a Hugo Blog with Travis on Git Push</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/03/18/hugo-blog-with-travis-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/03/18/hugo-blog-with-travis-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the Hugo build for wercker for a long time now. Recent problems occurred though where I did not understand at first what the problem was. It was quite difficult to debug since I did not have too much insight on the wercker build itself. Turned out that I deleted the GITHUB token that the process was using. However, the error message was telling me that a function failed to load some other function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go SSH with Host Key Verification</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/02/17/go-ssh-with-host-key-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 21:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2019/02/17/go-ssh-with-host-key-verification/</guid>
      <description>Go SSH with Host Key Verification</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensive tutorial on go-plugin.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/10/29/go-plugin-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 07:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/10/29/go-plugin-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>go-plugin tutorial</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace with a new Plugin System</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/09/17/furnace-plugin-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 07:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/09/17/furnace-plugin-update/</guid>
      <description>Furnace plugins</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOTP generator with account handling for multiple tokens</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/09/13/gotp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 08:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/09/13/gotp/</guid>
      <description>Gotp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your git forks updated all the time</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/06/08/fork-updater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 08:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/06/08/fork-updater/</guid>
      <description>Keep your git forks updated</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes distributed application deployment with sample Face Recognition App</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/03/15/kubernetes-distributed-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 23:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/03/15/kubernetes-distributed-application/</guid>
      <description>Intro Alright folks. Settle in and get comfortable. This is going to be a long, but hopefully, fun ride.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to deploy a distributed application with Kubernetes. I attempted to create an application that I thought resembled a real world app. Obviously I had to cut some corners due to time and energy constraints.
My focus will be on Kubernetes and deployment.
Shall we delve right in?
The Application TL;DR The application itself consists of six parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Budapest Meetup</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/02/06/go-budapest-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 23:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/02/06/go-budapest-meetup/</guid>
      <description>Intro So I was at Go Budapest Meetup yesterday, where the brilliant Johan Brandhorst gave a talk about his project based on gRPC using gRPC-web + GopherJS + protobuf. He also has some Go contributions and check out his project here: Protobuf. It&amp;rsquo;s GopherJS Bindings for ProtobufJS and gRPC-Web.
It was interesting to see where these projects could lead and I see the potential in them. I liked the usage of Protobuf and gRPC, I don&amp;rsquo;t have THAT much experience with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible &#43; Nginx &#43; LetsEncrypt &#43; Wiki &#43; Nagios</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/01/23/nginx-certbot-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 22:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/01/23/nginx-certbot-ansible/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Today, I would like demonstrate how to use Ansible in order to construct a server hosting multiple HTTPS domains with Nginx and LetsEncrypt. Are you ready? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
TL;DR What you will need There is really only one thing you need in order for this to work and that is Ansible. If you would like to run local tests without a remote server, than you will need Vagrant and VirtualBox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huge Furnace Update</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/01/13/furnace-massive-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 22:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/01/13/furnace-massive-update/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
In the past couple of months I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly updating Furnace.
There are three major changes that happened. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at them, shall we?
Google Cloud Platform Furnace now supports Google Cloud Platform (GCP). It provides the same API to handle GCP resource as with AWS. Namely, create, delete, status, update. I opted to leave out push because Google mostly works with git based repositories, meaning a push is literary just a push, than Google handles distributing the new code by itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commit-Build-Deploy With AWS CodeBuild and Lambda</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/12/04/commit-build-deploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 22:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/12/04/commit-build-deploy/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi All.
Today I would like to write about an AWS finger practice.
Previously, I wrote about how I build and deploy my blog with Wercker. Since, I&amp;rsquo;m a cloud engineer and I dislike Oracle and it&amp;rsquo;s ever expending tenctacles into the abyss, I wanted to switch to use something else.
My build and deploy cycle is simple.
Commit to Blogsource Repo -&amp;gt; Wercker WebHook -&amp;gt; Builds my blog using Hugo -&amp;gt; Pushed to a Different Repository which my Github Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace Ikea Manual</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/11/06/furnace-ikea-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 20:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/11/06/furnace-ikea-manual/</guid>
      <description>Hi there folks.
Just a quick post, of how I went on and created an IKEA manual about Furnace.
Page 1: . Page 2: .
I drew these using Krita. I mostly used a mouse but I also used a Wacom Bamboo drawing tabled, for sketches and such.
Thanks, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace Binaries</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/09/03/furnace-binaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 10:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/09/03/furnace-binaries/</guid>
      <description>Hey folks.
Quick note. Furnace now comes pre-compiled easy to access binaries which you can download and use out of the box.
No need to install anything, or compile the source. Just download, unzip and use.
Here is the website: Furnace Website.
Enjoy, Cheers, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notetaking</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/05/31/notetaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 06:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/05/31/notetaking/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Eval with Object.send and a self written Parser</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/05/28/replace-eval-with-object-send-and-a-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 19:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/05/28/replace-eval-with-object-send-and-a-parser/</guid>
      <description>Intro A while ago, I was added as a curator for a Gem called JsonPath. It&amp;rsquo;s a small but very useful and brilliant gem. It had a couple of problems which I fixed, but the hardest to eliminate proved to be a series of evals throughout the code.
You could opt in using eval with a constructor parameter, but generally, it was considered to be unsafe. Thus, normally when a project was using it, like Huginn they had to opt out by default, thus missing out on sweet parsing like this: $.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/04/16/building-furnace-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 09:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/04/16/building-furnace-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1. Part 2. Part 3.
In this part we are going to talk about Unit Testing Furnace and how to work some magic with AWS and Go.
Mock Stub Fake Dummy Canned Unit testing in Go usually follows the Dependency Injection model of dealing with Mocks and Stubs.
## DI
Dependency Inject in short is one object supplying the dependencies of another object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/22/building-furnace-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 12:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/22/building-furnace-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1. Part 2. Part 4.
In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the experimental plugin system of Furnace.
Go Experimental Plugins Since Go 1.8 was released, an exciting and new feature was introduced called a Plug-in system. This system works with dynamic libraries built with a special switch to go build. These libraries, .so or .dylib (later), are than loaded and once that succeeds, specific functions can be called from them (symbol resolution).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/19/building-furnace-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 12:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/19/building-furnace-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1, Part 3, Part 4
In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the AWS Go SDK and begin do dissect the intricacies of Furnace.
AWS SDK Fortunately, the Go SDK for AWS is quiet verbose and littered with examples of all sorts. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it less complex and less cryptic at times. I&amp;rsquo;m here to lift some of the early confusions, in hopes that I can help someone to avoid wasting time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing new Hugo if posts are generated properly</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/17/test-new-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 09:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/17/test-new-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/16/building-furnace-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 21:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/16/building-furnace-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Other posts: Part 2, Part 3, Part 4.
Building Furnace: Part 1 Intro Hi folks.
This is the first part of a 4 part series which talks about the process of building a middlish sized project in Go, with AWS. Including Unit testing and a experimental plugin feature.
The first part will talk about the AWS services used in brief and will contain a basic description for those who are not familiar with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images on older posts</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/03/images-on-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 18:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/03/images-on-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
Just a quick headsup, that older posts and images, may have been lost unfortunately, because I made the terrible mistake, when I migrated over from my old blog, that I forgot to download all the images from the remote host.
For lack of options, I deleted the images. :/ Sorry for the inconvencience!
Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to HTTPS with Hugo LetsEncrypt and HAProxy</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/02/15/how-to-https-with-hugo-letsencrypt-haproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 19:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/02/15/how-to-https-with-hugo-letsencrypt-haproxy/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Today, I would like to write about how to do HTTPS for a website, without the need to buy a certificate and set it up via your DNS provider. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin.
Abstract What you will achieve by the end of this post:
Every call to HTTP will be redirected to HTTPS via haproxy. HTTPS will be served with Haproxy and LetsEncrypt as the Certificate provider. Automatically update the certificate before its expiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do Google Sign-In with Go - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/11/02/google-signin-with-go-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/11/02/google-signin-with-go-part2/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi Folks.
This is a follow up on my previous post about Google Sign-In. In this post we will discover what to do with the information retrieved in the first encounter, which you can find here: Google Sign-In Part 1.
Forewords The Project Everything I did in the first post, and that I&amp;rsquo;m going to do in this example, can be found in this project: Google-OAuth-Go-Sample.
Just to recap, we left off previously on the point where we successfully obtained information about the user, with a secure token and a session initiated with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RScrap scraper</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/10/06/rscrap-ruby-scraping-with-cronjob-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/10/06/rscrap-ruby-scraping-with-cronjob-scripts/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hey folks.
So, there is this project called Huginn which I absolutely love.
But the thing is, that for a couple of scrappers ( at least for me ), I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spin up a whole rails app.
Hence, I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with RScrap. Which is a bunch of Ruby scripts run as cron jobs on a raspberry pi. And because I dislike emails as well, and most of the time, I don&amp;rsquo;t read them, I opted for a nicer solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget Home Theather with a Headless Raspberry Pi and Flirc for Remote Controlling</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/09/17/simple-hometheater-with-remote-and-flirc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/09/17/simple-hometheater-with-remote-and-flirc/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hello folks.
Today, I would like to tell you about my configuration for a low budget Home Theater setup.
My tools are as follows:
FLIRC Raspberry Pi 2 500G SSD An a good &amp;lsquo;ol wifi TL;DR Use Flirc for remote control, omxplayer for streaming the movie from an SSD on a headless PI controller via SSH and enjoy a nice, cold Lemon - Menta beer.
Flirc First, the remote control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always Go with []byte</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/08/19/always-go-with-bytes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/08/19/always-go-with-bytes/</guid>
      <description>Update: This post ignored the fact that this works for utf-8 characters only. Characters which are stored on more than 1 byte will cause trouble. Look at this Effective Go Example.
for pos, char := range &amp;#34;日本\x80語&amp;#34; { // \x80 is an illegal UTF-8 encoding fmt.Printf(&amp;#34;character %#U starts at byte position %d\n&amp;#34;, char, pos) } Prints:
character U+65E5 &amp;#39;日&amp;#39; starts at byte position 0 character U+672C &amp;#39;本&amp;#39; starts at byte position 3 character U+FFFD &amp;#39;�&amp;#39; starts at byte position 6 character U+8A9E &amp;#39;語&amp;#39; starts at byte position 7 Keep this in mind when working with strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global variable for never changing regex</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/08/16/never-changing-regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/08/16/never-changing-regex/</guid>
      <description>Quick reminder. If you have a never changing regex in Go, do NOT put it into a frequently called function. ALWAYS put it into a global variable. I&amp;rsquo;ll show you why.
Benchmark for code with a variable in a frequently called function:
BenchmarkNumber-8 30000	41633 ns/op BenchmarkAreaCode-8 50000	27736 ns/op BenchmarkFormat-8 50000	29263 ns/op PASS ok _/phone-number	5.110s Benchmark for code with the same variable outside in a global scope:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal missing ToolBar and settings not saving</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/08/13/drupal-missing-toolbar-and-settings-not-saving/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/08/13/drupal-missing-toolbar-and-settings-not-saving/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
Quick gotcha, when working with Drupal. If you just freshly installed it, and everything seems to work fine, and yet you are experiencing things like, the admin toolbar is randomly disappearing, or configuration is not saved; than you might not have modrewrite enabled on your apache server.
Because, by default, Drupal has clean url enabled, that needs URL rewriting on apache.
So, step one.
Have this in your .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins Best Practices Talk</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/07/28/jenkins-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/07/28/jenkins-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
I wanted to take the time to share with you a talk that I recently did.
The slides and the source I used, can be found here: Github.
And then, there is also a docker image which contains all the plugins, job configurations and all the practices which I did during the talk. Please feel free to have a go with it. DockerHub - Jenkins Best Practices.
For easy access and reading, here are the slides on Slideshare: Jenkins Best Practices Slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Sieve</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/07/12/ruby-sieve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/07/12/ruby-sieve/</guid>
      <description>Though it could be done better, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, but I&amp;rsquo;m actually pretty satisfied with this one. It loops only twice as opposed to filtered ranges and whatnot other solutions to the sieve. I was thinking of rather creating a list and deleting elements from it, but that&amp;rsquo;s already three loops.
Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll do a benchmark later on more solutions.
# Sieve contains a function to return a set of primes class Sieve def initialize(n) @n = n end # Returns a list of primes up to a certain limit # @param n limit # @return list of primes def primes marked = [] primes = [] (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple hook to rid of trouble</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/07/12/simple-hook-to-rid-of-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/07/12/simple-hook-to-rid-of-trouble/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
This is but a simple git hook to run a test in order to ensure you can push. It also ignores the vendor folder if you happen to have on in your directory.
Edit the file under .git/hooks/pre-push.sample and add this at the end before the exit 0.
go test $(go list ./... |grep -v vendor) RESULT=$? if [ $RESULT -ne 0 ]; then echo &amp;#34;Failed test run. Disallowing push.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do Google sign-in with Go</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/06/12/google-signin-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/06/12/google-signin-with-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I would like to write up a step - by - step guide with a sample web app on how to do Google Sign-In and authorization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft world automatic backup to AWS S3 bucket - Part 2 (Custom functions)</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/17/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/17/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got an update for the backup script. This time, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the ability to implement your own upload capabilities. I provide a mock implementation for the required functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the script again, now modified and a bit cleaned up. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft world automatic backup to AWS S3 bucket</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/16/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/16/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
Previously we created a Minecraft server using Docker. After my server got popular in the family, and a lot of stuff started to pile up on it, as a good IT person, I&amp;rsquo;m backing up the world once in a while.
For that, I&amp;rsquo;m using AWS S3 with the CLI and a little bash script which runs once a week.
The script is really straightforward. I&amp;rsquo;m doing manual versioning, although S3 does provide one out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft Server with Docker on OSX &#43; Mods</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/29/minecraft-server-with-docker-and-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/29/minecraft-server-with-docker-and-osx/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
Intro Today, I wanted to write about how to create a secure server in a container. Ideally, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to run your server on your own machine. Running it in a container gives you a much needed control and an extra layer of security.
Docker On OSX While on a mac, you have a couple of options to run docker.
Docker-Machine Docker-Machine
Docker machine is very simple. It just creates a Linux vm in the background on the given driver, for us it will be VirtualBox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wercker Fixed</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/09/wercker-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/09/wercker-fixed/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
So Wercker was not working. After a minor modification it seems to be okay now. The config file needed for it to work looks like this:
box: golang build: steps: - arjen/hugo-build: theme: redlounge deploy: steps: - install-packages: packages: git - leipert/git-push: gh_oauth: $GIT_TOKEN repo: skarlso/skarlso.github.io branch: master basedir: public The modification is the box type to golang and removed ssh-client from packages.
Thanks, Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wercker Test</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/04/wercker-test-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/03/04/wercker-test-2/</guid>
      <description>Basics This is a wercker Test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Autodeploy with Wercker and Github - Pages</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/10/hugo-autodeploy-with-wercker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/10/hugo-autodeploy-with-wercker/</guid>
      <description>There already is a nice tutorial on how to create github-pages with Hugo Here if you prefer deplying your pages to a different branch on the same repo. There is also a post about Wercker and Hugo Here deploying pages to said separate branch.
However, I took an easier approach on the matter with a completely separate branch for my blog source and my compiled github pages.
This blog sits here: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wercker Test</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/10/wercker-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/10/wercker-test/</guid>
      <description>Basics This is a wercker Test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing CORS in Go with Gin and JSON</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/02/doing-cors-in-go-with-gin-and-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/02/02/doing-cors-in-go-with-gin-and-json/</guid>
      <description>Basics Hello folks.
This will be a quick post about how to do CORS with jQuery, Gin in Go with a very simple ajax GET and Json.
I&amp;rsquo;m choosing JSON here because basically I don&amp;rsquo;t really like JSONP. And actually, it&amp;rsquo;s not very complicated to do CORS, it&amp;rsquo;s just hidden enough so that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t become transparent.
First, what is CORS? It&amp;rsquo;s Cross-Platform Resource Sharing. It has been invented so that without your explicit authorization in the header of a request, Javascript can&amp;rsquo;t reach outside of your domain and be potentially harmful to your visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey in advent of code</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/01/22/my-journey-in-advent-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/01/22/my-journey-in-advent-of-code/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
I wanted to share with you my tale of working through the problems with Advent Of Code.
It is a nice tale and there are a few things I learned from it, especially in Go, since I used that solve all of the problems. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Solving the problems The most important lesson I learned while doing these exercises was, how to solve these problems. A couple of them were simple enough to not have to over think it, but most of them got very tricky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving performance with byte slice and int map</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/01/05/improving-performance-with-byte-slice-and-int-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/01/05/improving-performance-with-byte-slice-and-int-map/</guid>
      <description>Hello Folks.
Today I would like to share with you my little tale of refactoring my solution to Advent Of Code Day 13.
It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely tale of action, adventure, drama, and comedy.
Let&amp;rsquo;s being with my first iteration of the problem.
package main import ( &amp;#34;bufio&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;math&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strconv&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strings&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/skarlso/goutils/arrayutils&amp;#34; ) var seatingCombinations = make([][]string, 0) var table = make(map[string][]map[string]int) var keys = make([]string, 0) //Person a person type Person struct { // neighbour *Person name string like int } func main() { file, _ := os.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Byte arrays and Channels</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/01/01/byte-arrays-and-channels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/01/01/byte-arrays-and-channels/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks and a Happy new Year!
Today, I would like to show you some interesting things you can do with channels. Consider the following simple example.
package main import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; func main() { generatedPassword := make(chan int, 100) correctPassword := make(chan int) defer close(generatedPassword) defer close(correctPassword) go passwordIncrement(generatedPassword) go checkPassword(generatedPassword, correctPassword) pass := &amp;lt;-correctPassword fmt.Println(pass) } func checkPassword(input &amp;lt;-chan int, output chan&amp;lt;- int) { for { p := &amp;lt;-input //Introduce lengthy operation here // time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Byte Array Instead of Strings</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/29/use-byte-array-instead-of-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/29/use-byte-array-instead-of-strings/</guid>
      <description>Hello Folks.
This is just a quick post on the topic and a reminder for myself and everybody to ALWAYS USE []BYTE INSTEAD OF STRINGS.
[]Byte is marginally faster than a simple Strings. In fact, I would say using []byte should be the standard instead of strings.
Sample code:
package solutions import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; const ( //INPUT input INPUT = &amp;#34;1321131112&amp;#34; //LIMIT limit LIMIT = 50 ) //LookAndSay translates numbers according to Look and Say algo func LookAndSay(s string, c chan string) { charCount := 1 look := &amp;#34;&amp;#34; for i := range s { if i+1 &amp;lt; len(s) { if s[i] == s[i+1] { charCount++ } else { look += fmt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Byte Slice Instead of Strings</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/29/use-byte-slice-instead-of-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/29/use-byte-slice-instead-of-strings/</guid>
      <description>Hello Folks.
This is just a quick post on the topic and a reminder for myself and everybody to ALWAYS USE []BYTE INSTEAD OF STRINGS.
[]Byte is marginally faster than a simple Strings. In fact, I would say using []byte should be the standard instead of strings.
Sample code:
package solutions import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; const ( //INPUT input INPUT = &amp;#34;1321131112&amp;#34; //LIMIT limit LIMIT = 50 ) //LookAndSay translates numbers according to Look and Say algo func LookAndSay(s string, c chan string) { charCount := 1 look := &amp;#34;&amp;#34; for i := range s { if i+1 &amp;lt; len(s) { if s[i] == s[i+1] { charCount++ } else { look += fmt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursive Letter Frequency Count</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/23/recursive-freq-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/23/recursive-freq-count/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody!
I wanted to do a sort post about word frequency count. I did it many times now and I was curious as how a recursive solution would perform as opposed to looping.
So I wrote it up quickly and added a few benchmarks with different sized data.
First&amp;hellip;. The code:
var freqMap = make(map[string]int, 0) func countLettersRecursive(s string) string { if len(s) == 0 { return s } freqMap[string(s[0])]++ return countLettersRecursive(s[1:]) } func countLettersLoop(s string) { for _, v := range s { freqMap[string(v)]++ } } Very simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/08/go-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/08/go-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Here is a little something I&amp;rsquo;ve put together, since I&amp;rsquo;m doing it a lot.
Go Development Environment
If I have a project I&amp;rsquo;d like to contribute, like GoHugo, I have to setup a development environment, because most of the times, I&amp;rsquo;m on a Mac. And on OSX things work differently. I like to work in a Linux environment since that&amp;rsquo;s what most of the projects are built on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome To My New Blog</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/07/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/12/07/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hello Folks Welcome to my new blog. I decided to move away for a number of reasons, but setting up a static page blog site is very cool if you don&amp;rsquo;t directly use a database. Since posts are just posts and I have a different way of hosting images, this really was just a matter of time.
And Hugo / Github pages provided the tools which made this move possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go JIRA API client</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/11/20/go-jira-api-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/11/20/go-jira-api-client/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
So, I was playing around and created a client for JIRA written in Go. It was nice to do some JSON transformation. And sending POSTS was really trivial.
It&amp;rsquo;s still in it&amp;rsquo;s infancy and I have a couple of more features I want to implement, but, here is the code.
package main import ( &amp;#34;bytes&amp;#34; &amp;#34;encoding/json&amp;#34; &amp;#34;flag&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;io/ioutil&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;net/http&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/BurntSushi/toml&amp;#34; ) var configFile = &amp;#34;~/.jira_config.toml&amp;#34; var parameter string var flags struct { Comment string Description string IssueKey string Priority string Resolution string Title string Project string } //Issue is a representation of a Jira Issue type Issue struct { Fields struct { Project struct { Key string `json:&amp;#34;key&amp;#34;` } `json:&amp;#34;project&amp;#34;` Summary string `json:&amp;#34;summary&amp;#34;` Description string `json:&amp;#34;description&amp;#34;` Issuetype struct { Name string `json:&amp;#34;name&amp;#34;` } `json:&amp;#34;issuetype&amp;#34;` Priority struct { ID string `json:&amp;#34;id&amp;#34;` } `json:&amp;#34;priority&amp;#34;` } `json:&amp;#34;fields&amp;#34;` } //Transition defines a transition json object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One Hundred Day GitHub Challenge</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/11/15/the-one-hundred-day-github-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/11/15/the-one-hundred-day-github-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today, I present to you the One Hundred Day Github Challenge.
The rules are simple:
Minimum of One commit every day for a Hundred days. Commit has to be meaningful but can be as little as a fix in a Readme.md. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are on vacation, there are no exceptions. There. Are. No. Exceptions. If you fail a day, you have to start over. No cheating. You only cheat yourself, so this is really up to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Progress Quest</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/11/09/go-progress-quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/11/09/go-progress-quest/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
I started to build a Progress Quest type of web app in Go.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to join, or just tag along, please drop by here =&amp;gt; Go Progress Quest and feel free to submit an issue if you have an idea, or would like to contribute!
I will try and document the Progress.
Thank you for reading!
Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kill a Program on Connecting to a specific WiFi – OSX</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/26/kill-a-program-on-connecting-to-a-specific-wifi-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/26/kill-a-program-on-connecting-to-a-specific-wifi-osx/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
If you have the tendency, like me, to forget that you are on the corporate VPN, or leave a certain software open when you bring your laptop to work, this might be helpful to you too.
It&amp;rsquo;s a small script which kills a program when you change your Wifi network.
Script:
#!/bin/bash function log { directory=&amp;#34;/Users/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/wifi_detect&amp;#34; log_dir_exists=true if [ ! -d $directory ]; then echo &amp;#34;Attempting to create =&amp;gt; $directory&amp;#34; mkdir -p $directory if [ !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular buffer in Go</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/15/circular-buffer-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/15/circular-buffer-in-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m proud of this one too. No peaking. I like how go let&amp;rsquo;s you do this kind of stuff in a very nice way.
package circular import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; //TestVersion testVersion const TestVersion = 1 //Buffer buffer type type Buffer struct { buffer []byte full int size int s, e int } //NewBuffer creates a new Buffer func NewBuffer(size int) *Buffer { return &amp;amp;Buffer{buffer: make([]byte, size), s: 0, e: 0, size: size, full: 0} } //ReadByte reads a byte from b Buffer func (b *Buffer) ReadByte() (byte, error) { if b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins Job DSL and Groovy goodness</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/15/jenkins-job-dsl-and-groovy-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/15/jenkins-job-dsl-and-groovy-goodness/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
Ever used Job DSL plugin for Jenkins? What is that you say? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s TEH most awesome plug-in for Jenkins to have, because you can CODE your job configuration and put it under source control.
Today, however, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to write about that because the tutorials on Jenkins JOB DSL are very extensive and very well done. Anyone can pick them up.
Today, I would like to write about a part of it which is even more interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataMunger Kata with Go</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/04/datamunger-kata-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/04/datamunger-kata-with-go/</guid>
      <description>Quickly wrote up the Data Munger code kata in Go.
Next time, I want better abstractions. And a way to select columns based on their header data. For now, this is not bad.
package main import ( &amp;#34;bufio&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;math&amp;#34; &amp;#34;os&amp;#34; &amp;#34;regexp&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strconv&amp;#34; &amp;#34;strings&amp;#34; ) //Data which is Data type Data struct { columnName string compareOne float64 compareTwo float64 } func main() { // datas := []Data{WeatherData{}, FootballData{}} fmt.Println(&amp;#34;Minimum weather data:&amp;#34;, GetDataMinimumDiff(&amp;#34;weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Aggregate Tests with Jenkins with Aggregate Plugin on non-relating jobs</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/02/how-to-aggregate-tests-with-jenkins-with-aggregate-plugin-on-non-relating-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/10/02/how-to-aggregate-tests-with-jenkins-with-aggregate-plugin-on-non-relating-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today, I would like to talk about something I came in contact with, and was hard to find a proper answer / solution for it.
So I&amp;rsquo;m writing this down to document my findings. Like the title says, this is about aggregating test result with Jenkins, using the plug-in provided. If you, like me, have a pipeline structure which do not work on the same artifact, but do have a upstream-downstream relationship, you will have a hard time configuring and making Aggregation work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/09/07/i-used-to-have-great-ideas-on-the-toilet-but-i-no-longer-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/09/07/i-used-to-have-great-ideas-on-the-toilet-but-i-no-longer-do/</guid>
      <description>I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do. And I would like to reflect on that. So this is not going to be a technical post, rather some ramblings.
I already had a post similar to this one, but I failed to follow up on it, and now I&amp;rsquo;m re-visiting the question. With technology on the rise, embedded systems, chips, augmented biology and information being available at our fingertips, I have but one concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sieve of Eratosthenes in Go</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/30/sieve-of-eratosthenes-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/30/sieve-of-eratosthenes-in-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty proud of this one as well.
package sieve //Sieve Uses the Sieve of Eratosthenes to calculate primes to a certain limit func Sieve(limit int) []int { var listOfPrimes []int markers := make([]bool, limit) for i := 2; i &amp;lt; limit; i++ { if !markers[i] { for j := i + i; j &amp;lt; limit; j += i { markers[j] = true } listOfPrimes = append(listOfPrimes, i) } } return listOfPrimes } </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip for Debugging Headless Locally</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/22/quick-tip-for-debugging-headless-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/22/quick-tip-for-debugging-headless-locally/</guid>
      <description>If you are installing something with Packer and you have Headless enabled(and you are lazy and don&amp;rsquo;t want to switch it off), it gets difficult, to see output.
Especially on a windows install the Answer File / Unattended install can be like =&amp;gt; Waiting for SSH. for about an hour or two! If you are doing this locally fret not. Just start VirtualBox, and watch the Preview section which will display the current state even if it&amp;rsquo;s a headless install!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting numbers into string representations</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/19/converting-numbers-into-string-representations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/19/converting-numbers-into-string-representations/</guid>
      <description>I quiet like this one. My first go program snippet without any peaking or googling. I&amp;rsquo;m proud, though it could be improved with a bit of struct magic and such and such. And it only counts &amp;rsquo;till 1000.
package main import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; var words = map[int]string{1: &amp;#34;one&amp;#34;, 2: &amp;#34;two&amp;#34;, 3: &amp;#34;three&amp;#34;, 4: &amp;#34;four&amp;#34;, 5: &amp;#34;five&amp;#34;, 6: &amp;#34;six&amp;#34;, 7: &amp;#34;seven&amp;#34;, 8: &amp;#34;eight&amp;#34;, 9: &amp;#34;nine&amp;#34;, 10: &amp;#34;ten&amp;#34;, 11: &amp;#34;eleven&amp;#34;, 12: &amp;#34;twelve&amp;#34;, 13: &amp;#34;thirteen&amp;#34;, 14: &amp;#34;fourteen&amp;#34;, 15: &amp;#34;fifteen&amp;#34;, 16: &amp;#34;sixteen&amp;#34;, 17: &amp;#34;seventeen&amp;#34;, 18: &amp;#34;eighteen&amp;#34;, 19: &amp;#34;nineteen&amp;#34;, 20: &amp;#34;twenty&amp;#34;, 30: &amp;#34;thirty&amp;#34;, 40: &amp;#34;forty&amp;#34;, 50: &amp;#34;fifty&amp;#34;, 60: &amp;#34;sixty&amp;#34;, 70: &amp;#34;seventy&amp;#34;, 80: &amp;#34;eighty&amp;#34;, 90: &amp;#34;ninety&amp;#34;} // CountLetters count the letters in a long string number representation func CountLetters(limit int) { myLongNumberString := &amp;#34;&amp;#34; for i := 1; i &amp;lt;= limit; i++ { addLettersToMyString(&amp;amp;myLongNumberString, i) } // fmt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium Testing with Packer and Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/16/selenium-testing-with-packer-and-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/16/selenium-testing-with-packer-and-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, recently, the tester team talked to me, that their build takes too long, and why is that? A quick look at their configuration and build scripts showed me, that they are actually using a vagrant box, which never gets destroyed or re-started at least. To remedy this problem, I came up with the following solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitwise &amp; Operator</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/15/bitwise-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/15/bitwise-operator/</guid>
      <description>The first, and only time so far, that I got to use the bitwise &amp;amp; operator. I enjoyed doing so!!
And of course from now on, I&amp;rsquo;ll be looking for more opportunities to (ab)use it.
package secret import &amp;#34;sort&amp;#34; const REVERSE = 16 func Handshake(code int) []string { // binary_rep := convertDecimalToBinary(code) if code &amp;lt; { return nil } secret_map := map[int]string { 1: &amp;#34;wink&amp;#34;, 2: &amp;#34;double blink&amp;#34;, 4: &amp;#34;close your eyes&amp;#34;, 8: &amp;#34;jump&amp;#34;, } var keys []int for k := range secret_map { keys = append(keys, k) } // To make sure iteration is always in the same order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packer 0.8.1.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/01/packer-0-8-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/01/packer-0-8-1/</guid>
      <description>Previously I wrote that the scripts I&amp;rsquo;m writing, are failing because Packer hangs.
Apparently, this was a known issue. And apparently, I was using an older version, 0.7.5. After I updated everything is working wonderfully!!!
And for my thanks, here is an updated PowerShell script for provisioning my dotnet stuff.
$source = &amp;#34;http://download.microsoft.com/download/1/6/7/167F0D79-9317-48AE-AEDB-17120579F8E2/NDP451-KB2858728-x86-x64-AllOS-ENU.exe&amp;#34; $destination = &amp;#34;C:\Windows\Temp\dotnet.exe&amp;#34; Write-Host &amp;#39;Starting to download dotnet file.&amp;#39; try { (New-Object System.Net.WebClient).DownloadFile($source, $destination) } catch [Exception] { Write-Host &amp;#34;Exception during download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell can also be nice -Or Installing Java silently and waiting</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/06/30/powershell-can-also-be-nice-or-installing-java-silently-and-waiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/06/30/powershell-can-also-be-nice-or-installing-java-silently-and-waiting/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today, I would like to show you a small script. It installs Java JDK, both version, x86 and 64 bit, silently, and wait for that process to finish.
The wait is necessary because /s on a java install has the nasty habit of running in the background. If you are using a .bat file, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, than you would use something like: start /w jdk-setup.exe /s. This gets it done, but is ugly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Packer, The Windows, and the Vagrant box</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/06/27/the-packer-the-windows-and-the-vagrant-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/06/27/the-packer-the-windows-and-the-vagrant-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I would like to write about something close to my heart recently. I&amp;rsquo;ve been fiddling with Packer, Windows and Vagrant these days. Trying to get a Windows box up in running is a pain in the arse though, so I thought I share my pain with you nice folks out there. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &#43; Java &#43; Vagrant&#43; GO.CD</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/06/06/docker-ruby-lotus-go-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/06/06/docker-ruby-lotus-go-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I would like to write about something interesting and close to me at the moment. I&amp;rsquo;m going to setup Go.cd with Docker, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a Ruby Lotus app running. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a new Laptop with Puppet</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/21/setting-up-a-new-laptop-with-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/21/setting-up-a-new-laptop-with-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
So, some of you know puppet, some of you don&amp;rsquo;t. Puppet is a configuration management system. It&amp;rsquo;s quite awesome. I like working with it. One of the benefits of puppet is, that I never, ever, EVER have to setup a new laptop from scratch, EVER again.
I&amp;rsquo;m writing a puppet manifest file which sets up my new laptop to my liking. I will improve it as I go along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy building the future</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/19/busy-building-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/19/busy-building-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Fact is, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy.
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new job as a build engineer. As sort of a devops kind of guy. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely interesting considering that I made a career as a tester. Granted, I always was technical, and never really knew my path; but it seems my path is finding me after all.
In the past years, I got better at Docker, Puppet, Chef, AWS, Packer, Vagrant, Gradle, and a hell of a lot more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django – RPG – Part 3</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/21/django-rpg-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/21/django-rpg-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
A small update to this. I created the model now, which is the database design for this app. It&amp;rsquo;s very simple, nothing fancy. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m writing the app with Python 3 from now on.
Here is the model now:
from django.db import models from django.contrib.auth.models import User # Create your models here. class Item(models.Model): name = models.CharField(max_length=100, default=&amp;#34;Item&amp;#34;) damage = models.IntegerField(default=) defense = models.IntegerField(default=) consumable = models.BooleanField(default=False) def __str__(self): return self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django – RPG – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/12/django-rpg-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/12/django-rpg-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing where we left off with the Django RPG project. Next up is implementing a rudimentary registration and adding the ability to create a character. Maybe even, design the database through django&amp;rsquo;s modelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django – RPG – Part 1</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/10/django-rpg-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/10/django-rpg-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last time, we tried to implement a little RPG of mine using Meteor, which failed miserably. This time we are going to try and use Django. Let&amp;rsquo;s have at it, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Python GUI to Calculate Lever Distance</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/10/small-python-gui-to-calculate-lever-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/04/10/small-python-gui-to-calculate-lever-distance/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
Just a small script which calculates your distance from a lever focal point if you know your weight, the object&amp;rsquo;s weight and the object&amp;rsquo;s and the distance the object has from the focal point of the lever.
Like this:
This script will give you D1. And this is how it will look like in doing so:
So, in order for me (77kg) to lift an object of 80kg which is on a, by default, 1 meter long lever, I have to stand back ~1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python and my Math commitment</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/03/15/python-and-my-math-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/03/15/python-and-my-math-commitment/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about plans. It&amp;rsquo;s good to have one. For example, I have a plan for this year.
I kind of like math. So, I have this book:
It&amp;rsquo;s 1400 pages long and basically, has everything in it. It&amp;rsquo;s a rather exhaustive book. Hence, my plan is to finish the book by the end of 2015 and write a couple of python scripts that calculate something interesting.
(2021 Hindsight): Yeah, I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage this&amp;hellip; But it&amp;rsquo;s a cool idea, let&amp;rsquo;s see if I can get around coming further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sphere Judge Online – Python Kivy Android app – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/03/02/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/03/02/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Here we are again. I will attempt to further this little journey of mine into the land of Android and Python.
This is the second part of the advanture you can read the first one a little bit back.
The Script We left off at a point where I successfully configured my environment and compiled my first hello world APK. At that point it took a little bit fiddling to get it to work on my phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sphere Judge Online – Python Kivy Android app</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/26/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/26/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today I would like to take you on a journey I fought myself through in order to write a python android app, which gets you a random problem from Sphere Judge Online. Then you can mark it as solved and it will be stored as such, and you can move on to the next problem. With the words of Neil deGrasse Tyson, Come with Me!
Beginnings When I first embarked on this endeavour I ran into numerous errors, many amongst them being compilation issues when I was trying to install libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Lock Picking is like Testing</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/08/why-lock-picking-is-like-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/08/why-lock-picking-is-like-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a great many people know that I&amp;rsquo;m actually into Lock Picking as a hobby. This will not be a tutorial on how to do it, or I won&amp;rsquo;t really talk about how I do it; I would like to write about something completely different. So if you came here for that, here are a few very good resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lockpicking101.com/%20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lockpicking101.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.lockpicking101.com/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/a&gt;- Tutorials&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ukbumpkeys.com/collections/lock-picking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ukbumpkeys.com/collections/lock-picking&#34;&gt;http://www.ukbumpkeys.com/collections/lock-picking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Tools ( UK )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/lockpicking/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/lockpicking/&#34;&gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/lockpicking/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Reddit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my post, click on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an RPG App with Meteor – Part One – The struggle</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/01/building-an-rpg-app-with-meteor-part-one-the-struggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/01/building-an-rpg-app-with-meteor-part-one-the-struggle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my previous post, I was getting ready to enjoy some time with the JavaScript web framework Meteor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I would like to bring it to a bit of overdrive. See, how re-factoring works on a larger scale model with multiple pages. And how it can organize assets, such as, images, multiple CSS, some plugins, you know, ordinary web stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Web Framework – Meteor</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/29/javascript-web-framework-meteor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/29/javascript-web-framework-meteor/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
This time I would like to write about something that interests me. I wanted to try out a pure JavaScript web framework.
My choice is: Meteor. Looks interesting enough and it was recommended by a friend of mine. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
Installation As always, one starts with installation. The page tells us to follow this simple step:
curl https://install.meteor.com/ | sh Easy enough, when you are on Linux. Turns out, that there is no official release yet for Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When cucumber goes wrong</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/28/when-cucumber-goes-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/28/when-cucumber-goes-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
Let&amp;rsquo;s face the horrible truth:
It&amp;rsquo;s rare / never happens that a manager / scrum master / product owner actually reads your cucumber test cases.
Back in the old days, this was one of the selling points of human readable tests and DSLs. It sounds nice and I&amp;rsquo;m sure in a utopia it also works.
BDD is a very nice approach to write tests if used in a correct way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Zero to Hundred in Four seconds</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/27/from-zero-to-hundred-in-four-seconds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/27/from-zero-to-hundred-in-four-seconds/</guid>
      <description>I thought I throw my grudge out of the window against Scala and try something with it.
I also got my hands on a fairly new book, called: &amp;ldquo;Learning Scala: Practical Functional Programming for the JVM&amp;rdquo;. Turns out to be a rather fun book to read. And Jason Swartz has a nice way of writing. So I wanted to play around with Play 2 Framework. It now comes packaged in Activator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Testers are, like scientists</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/26/why-testers-are-like-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/26/why-testers-are-like-scientists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I would like to write about little observation I made along the way of being a tester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title says it all. I think Testers, are like scientists. I would go even further, and say: Testers, are scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us see how the two compare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the expressiveness of your Tests is important – Part One</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/11/15/why-the-expressiveness-of-your-tests-is-important-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/11/15/why-the-expressiveness-of-your-tests-is-important-part-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I&amp;rsquo;d like to write about the expressiveness of a Test. I think that it&amp;rsquo;s very important to write understandable and expressive tests. In older times I was studying novel writing. There is a rule which a novel needs to follow. It goes something like this: &amp;ldquo;A novel needs to lead its reader and make him understand in the simplest way what&amp;rsquo;s going on, with whom and why?&amp;rdquo;. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s not a puzzle. It should be obvious what the test is trying to do and it should not require the reader to try and solve it in order to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating All Jenkins Jobs Via Jenkins API – Python</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/11/07/updating-all-jenkins-jobs-via-jenkins-api-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/11/07/updating-all-jenkins-jobs-via-jenkins-api-python/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
I would like to share with you a small script I wrote to update all, or a single, Jenkins job from a Python script remotely.
This will enable you to update a Jenkins job from anywhere using an admin credential based on a config.xml template that you have. With this, if you want to apply a config change to all or just a single job in Jenkins, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to go and do it for all the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The seven Principles of Context Driven Testing – Mind Map</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/10/23/the-seven-guidelines-of-context-driven-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/10/23/the-seven-guidelines-of-context-driven-testing/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks!
I just wanted to share with you my mind map on the seven principles of Context Driven Testing.
I used the notion of dragons since it&amp;rsquo;s seven. And a dragon is usually seven headed in my mind.
So without further ado.
Click for larger image.
I have a hand drawn as well but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that one wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be of much use since it follows my own imagination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Course Review</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/08/25/python-course-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/08/25/python-course-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to write a little bit about a python course I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an 8 week course on algorithmic programming with fun little projects. I&amp;rsquo;d like to write down some of my solutions with pseudo code for my own better understanding and for the sake of sharing knowledge. I won&amp;rsquo;t, however, share full projects since that would be against the honour code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five reasons why a tester should learn SQL</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/31/five-reasons-why-a-tester-should-learn-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/31/five-reasons-why-a-tester-should-learn-sql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last I was writing about why a tester should learn Javascript. Today I would like to write about why a tester should learn SQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There, I said it. I know many people, especially testers, don&amp;rsquo;t like SQL. They view it as a monster best be avoided. Something only Database people will know. Something which is so scary and ugly, nobody really wants it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I will give you a couple of good reasons why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of SQL. And why you should welcome it as your best friend and partner in crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD is Dead – Not really</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/26/tdd-is-dead-not-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/26/tdd-is-dead-not-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is TDD dead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really. So let&amp;rsquo;s talk about this topic for a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you already read a gazillion posts about this debate but frankly I&amp;rsquo;m writing this for myself, to rant a little bit, you know. Because somebody is wrong on the internet and I must intervene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five reasons why a front-end tester should learn Javascript</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/23/five-reasons-why-a-front-end-tester-should-learn-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/23/five-reasons-why-a-front-end-tester-should-learn-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to write about a very interesting topic, I hope. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the title already suggests, I&amp;rsquo;m writing about why a front-end tester should learn at least a little bit about JavaScripting and the DOM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohhh and contrary to the belief CSP ( Content Security Policy ) will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be the death of such scripts. There are white-lists and workarounds and exclusions which can be implemented in order to allow local JavaScripting to continue. So don&amp;rsquo;t fret. Read on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking what when how often</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/20/note-taking-what-when-how-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/20/note-taking-what-when-how-often/</guid>
      <description>Hello Everybody.
Today I would like to tell you about a little conversation I had with my friend Adrian.
The topic was about how, when and what to log during a testing session regarding a story.
So let&amp;rsquo;s see what came out of that talk.
Logging your work
The question is really not whether you should log your work or not, but rather to what extend. Because we all know that you should log your work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Chrome Search Engine – Multiple Search Params</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/18/using-chrome-search-engine-multiple-search-params/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/18/using-chrome-search-engine-multiple-search-params/</guid>
      <description>Hello Everybody.
Today I would like to write a few words about Chrome&amp;rsquo;s Search Engines.
You&amp;rsquo;re probably already using it for a couple of things, like Google, or Amazon searches or YouTube or anything like that. But are you using it to access environments and testing tools faster, with queries?
For example, here is a quick Jira Search made easy:
Keyword: jira
URL: https://atlas.projectname.com/jira/browse/PROJECT-%s
So just type: jira|space|9999
Will immediately bring you to your ticket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started Running</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/16/how-i-started-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/16/how-i-started-running/</guid>
      <description>Hello Everybody.
Today I would like to write about something non-technical. I would like to write about running and how I started it and what my experiences were with it.
So tl;dr. here we go.
What led me to running
There were actually two things that led me to start running. Three.
Reason One: The accident
I&amp;rsquo;m a bike person by default. I *hate running with a passion. One day I was riding my bike in the woods when suddenly I hit a big ol&amp;rsquo; tree trunk right head on at which moment my bikes front fork bent inwards and became completely useless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the past influences the present</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/04/13/how-the-past-influences-the-present/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/04/13/how-the-past-influences-the-present/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only a quick rant about a discussion I overheard the other day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example when to use the Strategy Pattern</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/19/example-when-to-use-the-strategy-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/19/example-when-to-use-the-strategy-pattern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick post about an interesting idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to elaborate on a possibility to use the Strategy Design pattern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a blog – Why long posts rarely work</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/13/how-to-write-a-blog-why-long-posts-rarely-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/13/how-to-write-a-blog-why-long-posts-rarely-work/</guid>
      <description>Hello.
So let&amp;rsquo;s clarify this. They rarely or ever work if you are a beginner blogger. If you have a reputation it will probably work or people will use it as a reference. But I&amp;rsquo;m skipping ahead.
Beginnings
When you are a beginner blog writer you want to get out as much content as possible. Write mostly relevant things and interesting information because you need to establish a name for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to check content header on unknown number of items – Python</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/11/how-to-check-content-header-on-unknown-number-of-items-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/11/how-to-check-content-header-on-unknown-number-of-items-python/</guid>
      <description>Hello guys.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to share a little something with you. It&amp;rsquo;s what I cooked up in Python to check an unknown number of content items in a web application.
Basically the script runs from a script folder under Grails. It goes through all the configured folders where there is static content like images, javascript, css and so on and so forth.
And then with curl it calls these items up in using their respective paths&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The method of Loci and how it works for me</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/11/the-method-of-loci-and-how-it-works-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/11/the-method-of-loci-and-how-it-works-for-me/</guid>
      <description>Hello.
Today I would like to write about something very interesting to you folks.
It&amp;rsquo;s a common remember / recall technique called the Method of loci. Otherwise known as the Memory Palace. A very popular usage can be seen in the episodes of Sherlock Holmes from BBC. He uses it often.
What is the Method of loci?
As the Wikipedia page write so properly.&amp;ldquo;In basic terms, it is a method of memory enhancement which uses visualization to organize and recall information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should learn using Vim</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/10/why-you-should-learn-using-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/10/why-you-should-learn-using-vim/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
So Vim is a very powerful editing tool and has lots and lots of potential in regarding plug-ins.
It has years and years of gathered knowledge and extensions and can virtually do anything you want. But that&amp;rsquo;s not even it&amp;rsquo;s final form.
The real power of Vim lies in navigation and manipulation. The ability to navigate and edit without the use of arrow keys or mouse chops of a large portion of your time which you didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize you are wasting until you try it without it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does it matter if I sit in an office or in a park</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/09/why-does-it-matter-if-i-sit-in-an-office-or-in-a-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/09/why-does-it-matter-if-i-sit-in-an-office-or-in-a-park/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to explain a lot about a topic that is very near my heart. If your job is in an office you will understand this.
Why offices?
So why are we sitting together in one big place cramped up with 20-300 other people? Why bother the catering and the ventilation and what not to accommodate these people at one place? Why not just leave them be and let them work at home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I recruit – Why tool requirements are stupid</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/04/how-i-recruit-why-tool-requirements-are-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/04/how-i-recruit-why-tool-requirements-are-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Today I would like to write about something very interesting I&amp;rsquo;m seeing all over the place from recruiters. And that is tool requirements from developers.
For words
So why is it a problem that in a requirement from a developer there a lots of these:
DB2 QTP Ranorex Eclipse ( yes I saw a few of these. ) Hibernate Grails Ruby on Rails . Long answer
The answer is simple yet it has it&amp;rsquo;s roots very deep in the recruitment and the way companies work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should care about the quality of your test code</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/11/02/why-you-should-care-about-the-quality-of-your-test-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/11/02/why-you-should-care-about-the-quality-of-your-test-code/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today I would like to talk to you about something interesting I was talking about with a developer friend.
We talked about the quality of test code.
He said. And I will quote this.&amp;ldquo;Why should we care? It&amp;rsquo;s not production code. We aren&amp;rsquo;t giving it to the customer.&amp;rdquo;
There are a few reasons why you are going to get a slap in the face for a sentence like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Bit</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/10/11/diary-of-a-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/10/11/diary-of-a-bit/</guid>
      <description>Dear everbody.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to present you a small idea I was working on recently. The reminiscence of an old program. From the view point of the program.
I&amp;rsquo;m planning to put these out in few days successions.
I hope you enjoy it.
Cheers,
Gergely.
If I remember correctly it was the year 2012 when I was born. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure of this date as my subroutines and algorithms have been re-written so many times that if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for my backups I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t remember a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Tech – Why having less will fell more</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/08/26/low-tech-why-having-less-will-fell-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/08/26/low-tech-why-having-less-will-fell-more/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to share today something with all of you. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about how technology affected my life in the long run. And how I perceive the world today around me. So let&amp;rsquo;s go around this topic for a little bit shall we?
The Past
So as somebody who lived for a while without technology coming near family for a decade or so I have a little bit of past in me without smart phones, gadgets, tv or computers for that matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why not to automate everything…</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/07/31/why-not-to-automate-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/07/31/why-not-to-automate-everything/</guid>
      <description>Hello. I created a tale of why not to automate everything. With legos. Enjoy.
Gergely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime text</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/06/24/sublime-text-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/06/24/sublime-text-5/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody. I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around with sublime for some time now. And been using it to write entires and stuff. So here I was thinking why the hell I should not us it as my main blog entry writer. And being the curious guy I was I thought that creating a plugin that let&amp;rsquo;s you submit your post from your favorite editor is just the thing I need.
So without any further ado here it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber-Jvm And @AfterAll</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/18/cucumber-jvm-and-afterall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/18/cucumber-jvm-and-afterall/</guid>
      <description>Hey folks.
I find out something new about cucumber-jvm every day.
If you want something that is executed after all of the tests have finished you must use the Java shutdownHook. It&amp;rsquo;s simple really you add in a block of code that can run right before the JVM quits. I know I know. It sounds awful but I found out that this is the actual way of doing this with java / cucumber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber Test Name and Tags on Feature</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/15/cucumber-test-name-and-tags-on-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/15/cucumber-test-name-and-tags-on-feature/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
I would like to show you a gem today that I found out.
Apparently there is no easy way to get to the name of an executing cucumber scenario in cucumber-jvm
You can try something like that:
@After //this is cucumbers @Afters public static void afterExecution(Scenario scenario) { logger.log(&amp;#34;The status of the test is: &amp;#34; + scenario.getStatus()); } But that isn&amp;rsquo;t giving you too much now is it? And the API of scenario is as small as it can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groovy and Grails course summary</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/11/groovy-and-grails-course-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/11/groovy-and-grails-course-summary/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
I attended a 4 day course of Groovy and Grails and this is my attempt at writing up a summary to see how much I retained. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to do this from the top of my head without peaking at my notes.
So let&amp;rsquo;s begin.
Introductions
First of all, introductions. The course was held by Peter Ledbrook. He is the guy who wrote Grails in Action. He is awesome, go check him out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My history in testing</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/11/my-history-in-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/04/11/my-history-in-testing/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you some of the experiences I had as a beginner tester. I hope it sets you off on a path to enlightenment and leaves you off with a good appetite for testing. Shall we begin then?
The early days
It was 2004 when I finished school and started working at my first company. I finished as a software developer which is kind of an exaggeration since I only finished a 2 years course of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s all about human interaction.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/31/its-all-about-human-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/31/its-all-about-human-interaction/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
Today I would like to write about something I experienced over the years of being in the software industry.
Some History
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a tester for a long time now. I&amp;rsquo;ve been up and down and down and up. I struggled for a very long time until I became somebody who I am today. And I still have many things to learn ahead of me.
I learned from many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What you really need to know to become a Testing Expert</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/21/what-you-really-need-to-become-a-testing-expert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/21/what-you-really-need-to-become-a-testing-expert/</guid>
      <description>Hello Everybody.
Today I would like to show you what you need to become a Testing expert.
If you had noticed I deliberately left out the word Software. Why? Because becoming and expert in Testing Anything has the same root as becoming an expert to test software. And for that let me take you back to a Galaxy Far Far Away in Time AND Space.
The beginnings.
I went to school in Oroszlany, my home town in Hungary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Chaos There Shall Be Order</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/04/from-chaos-there-shall-be-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/04/from-chaos-there-shall-be-order/</guid>
      <description>Dear Readers.
Today I want to talk to you about something I discovered over years of working and experience.
Also something that I can see in the world repeating over and over again. Not just in Software business but also in History in Human nature in Physics and Systems.
So let&amp;rsquo;s see what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about.
What is Chaos?
Chaos is a state of utter confusion. Chaos is the opposite of order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methodologies, Thought Patterns, Lies</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/12/12/methodologies-thought-patterns-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/12/12/methodologies-thought-patterns-lies/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to write about something I discovered over the years of researching and following certain people and movements in Testing and Programming world.
Let me tell you that there are quite an amazing amount of stuff to be read out there. It&amp;rsquo;s overwhelming.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Methodologies first.
There are many out there currently. In programming and in testing too. Many speak of ways how you should or should not do you work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEAS: Testing Exploration Adventure Session</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/12/01/teas-testing-exploration-adventure-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/12/01/teas-testing-exploration-adventure-session/</guid>
      <description>Hello Everybody.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce T.E.A.S. to you. This is something I came up with yesterday which requires a lot of fantasy some good thinking planning and enthusiastic people. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
What is it about?
Testing Exploration Adventure Session is about. Testing! There. No real surprise, eh? TEAS has it&amp;rsquo;s roots in RPGs. Role Playing Games. If you ever heard or read about M.A.G.U.S. or the more known Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons you will have a better understanding of the concept behind this phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to eliminate a parameter boom</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/10/09/how-to-eliminate-a-parameter-boom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/10/09/how-to-eliminate-a-parameter-boom/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today I want to write about a little trick I learned.
If you are working with legacy code and you don&amp;rsquo;t have the chance to eliminate core design problems, you can use this little pattern to help you out.
Problem
Problem is that you have a class that has a gazillion collaborators and at some point in time one of the clever devs thought it would be a cool idea to do dependancy injection via the constructor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coderetreat London</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/30/89/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/30/89/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
So yesterday I was on a little gathering called Coderetreat.
If you look at the link you can read everything about it. If not, I&amp;rsquo;ve provided a short description.
What it is about?
So what is codereatreat about? In short it&amp;rsquo;s about programmers getting together and honing and practicing there skills in order to become more at what they are doing. It&amp;rsquo;s a practice run with great people. TDDing one problem the whole day long with constantly applied constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What my brain is up to the whole day…</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/20/what-my-brain-is-up-to-the-whole-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/20/what-my-brain-is-up-to-the-whole-day/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Here is a little graphic I made to show what my brain is up to the whole day long. Excuse me for the lack of my colouring skills. Enjoy
![Brain]1
Thanks for reading!
Gergely.
http://dl.dropbox.com/u/7604030/barinColored.jpg&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning programming with a visual mind</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/09/learning-programming-with-a-visual-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/09/09/learning-programming-with-a-visual-mind/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
Today I want to write to you about learning something with a visual mind. There are a gazillion posts out there that tell you how to learn something with a visual mind. However, there are only a few actually describing how to learn something as complicated and logical as programming. How do you draw up a function? How do you draw up a cycle or a structure?
Actually these are really easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD and Game of Life</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/07/12/tdd-and-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/07/12/tdd-and-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>So today at 8-12PM I had a great session with two friends of mine. It was awesome. Like a mini code retreat.
We set down in a musky bar, drank wine and beer and cider, and decided to practice some TDD with the well known problem of Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life. This challenge is really interesting. I never done it before, ever. So it was a really good practice for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey into an unknown system</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/28/journey-into-an-unknown-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/28/journey-into-an-unknown-system/</guid>
      <description>Aka, what you can do if you are facing and unknown framework / system you have to work with for quite some time.
Get intimate
You are going to live with this system for a while. The best thing you can do is getting to know it better. You have to get it to know like you would approche a fine lady. You have to ask it questions look after it, how it feels how its day was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solution to Wrap Kata</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/26/solution-to-wrap-kata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/26/solution-to-wrap-kata/</guid>
      <description>My solution to the String Wrap Kata. The goal is to have it wrap a text on a given column width.
It is not the best solution but this is my first try. I did it with TDD so there were tests first, which I&amp;rsquo;m not going to copy in..
public class WrapKata { public String wrap(String input, int columnSize) { if (input.length() &amp;lt;= columnSize) return input; else { return wrapLines(input, columnSize); } } private String wrapLines(String input, int columnSize) { int breakPoint = getBreakPoint(input, columnSize); String head = createHead(input, breakPoint); String tail = createTail(input, breakPoint); return head += &amp;#34;\n&amp;#34; + wrap(tail, columnSize); } private String createTail(String input, int breakPoint) { return input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read a professional book for slow learners</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/18/how-to-read-a-professional-book-for-slow-learners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/18/how-to-read-a-professional-book-for-slow-learners/</guid>
      <description>Hi everybody.
Today I want to talk to you about.. Well.. How to read a professional book for slow learners without too much waste of time.
Let us start at the. well. the beginning. How do you normally read a book if you want to memorize it properly. You read it once and then re read the whole thing again until it gets in your head? Or do you have another strategy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t throw Exception</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/dont-throw-exception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/dont-throw-exception/</guid>
      <description>Hi.
Today I want to talk about a common problem in many frameworks I encountered over the course of my carrier as a Java dev / automation engineer, whatnot.
Throwing Exceptions. That is in your method you have something like this:
public void insertMethodNameHere(String param) throws Exception {} This is bad. And I will tell you in short forms why.
Hides exceptions
This one should be obvious. When a method throws exception you can never be sure what kind of exceptions it handles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a professional blog</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/how-to-write-a-professional-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/how-to-write-a-professional-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
I want to write a little bit about writing a professional blog.
Early steps
Let&amp;rsquo;s first talk about what you understand about professional blog. It&amp;rsquo;s either a semi professional one, that mixes life with professionalism, like chess, programming, testing, painting, drawing, engineering whatever your profession is. Or it can be a purely professional one without your life getting involved in it.
Either way you have to decide at the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making your code understandable</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/making-your-code-understandable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/making-your-code-understandable/</guid>
      <description>Hi!
I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this many times over and over again. Many people have wrote books about it already. Like Uncle Bob&amp;rsquo;s Clean Code. Like Pragmatic Programmer by Andrew Hunt and David Thomas. What makes your code understandable to others.
Is it Comments?
No. It&amp;rsquo;s not comments. If your code could be read properly you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need comments to explain what it does. Like Uncle Bob said. A good code doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain surprises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Dual Card to work on Ubuntu 12.04.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/04/11/getting-dual-card-to-work-on-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/04/11/getting-dual-card-to-work-on-ubuntu-12-04/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys.
Today I want to talk about a little adventure I had yesterday night. It was quite the fun and frustration too. But neither comes without the other when it&amp;rsquo;s about linux.
So let us see what the problem is at hand. The problem machine is a Dell Inspiron N5110 with Nvidia card number one: GeForce GT 525M. And number two: Integrated. Optimus for the win.
So how windows is handling this is actually with a software called Optimus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMS Connection setup and Framework</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/03/04/jms-connection-setup-and-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/03/04/jms-connection-setup-and-framework/</guid>
      <description>Hello chumps.
Today I want to write about jms connection testing with a small framework. I wrote a small thing using a factory object model. It&amp;rsquo;s a lead, a proof of concept. You can use this to go onward.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s begin with the JMS connection it self.
JMS Connection
First rule of thumb is: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t wait for a response when dealing with JMS queues.&amp;rdquo; How so? Because, a JMS queue is asynchronous so you wont get back anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/27/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/27/configuration/</guid>
      <description>When I see something like this:
public class Config { public static final string DATABASELINK = &amp;#34;linkhere&amp;#34;; . . . } It sends a small, but chilling shiver down my spine. Just. don&amp;rsquo;t. There are a lot of possibilities to use configuration in Java. Java property files. Xml. Xml serialization. CSV file. Whatever suits you best, but this? DON&amp;rsquo;T!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello and welcome</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/26/hello-and-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/26/hello-and-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello Dear Visitor.
Welcome to the ramblings of a software test engineer who thinks that he is a tester but feels like a developer but works as a tester but wants to learn programming like a developer. And so on and so fort.
I will make a journey that has been done by many automation testers. The journey when you decide to step one forward. A friend of mine told me that it is good that a tester learns proper programming and that more should do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing ‘code’ tag.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/26/testing-code-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/26/testing-code-tag/</guid>
      <description>Hello.
This is just a quick post to test the working of the code tag.
Given(/The Action is ([A-z]*)/) do |action| @action = action end Perfect!!
The name of the plugin is WP-Syntax. The trick is to edit the page in plain HTML. Because the WordPress word editor screws up the &amp;lt;&amp;gt; tags. But surely you already knew that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
