<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rambling on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/rambling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rambling on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/rambling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/09/07/i-used-to-have-great-ideas-on-the-toilet-but-i-no-longer-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/09/07/i-used-to-have-great-ideas-on-the-toilet-but-i-no-longer-do/</guid>
      <description>I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do. And I would like to reflect on that. So this is not going to be a technical post, rather some ramblings.
I already had a post similar to this one, but I failed to follow up on it, and now I’m re-visiting the question. With technology on the rise, embedded systems, chips, augmented biology and information being available at our fingertips, I have but one concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip for Debugging Headless Locally</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/22/quick-tip-for-debugging-headless-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/22/quick-tip-for-debugging-headless-locally/</guid>
      <description>If you are installing something with Packer and you have Headless enabled(and you are lazy and don’t want to switch it off), it gets difficult, to see output.
Especially on a windows install the Answer File / Unattended install can be like =&amp;gt; Waiting for SSH… for about an hour or two! If you are doing this locally fret not. Just start VirtualBox, and watch the Preview section which will display the current state even if it’s a headless install!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy building the future</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/19/busy-building-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/19/busy-building-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Fact is, I’ve been busy.
I’ve got a new job as a build engineer. As sort of a devops kind of guy. It’s extremely interesting considering that I made a career as a tester. Granted, I always was technical, and never really knew my path; but it seems my path is finding me after all.
In the past years, I got better at Docker, Puppet, Chef, AWS, Packer, Vagrant, Gradle, and a hell of a lot more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD is Dead – Not really</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/26/tdd-is-dead-not-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/26/tdd-is-dead-not-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is TDD dead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really. So let’s talk about this topic for a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you already read a gazillion posts about this debate but frankly I’m writing this for myself, to rant a little bit, you know… Because somebody is wrong on the internet and I must intervene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking what when how often</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/20/note-taking-what-when-how-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/20/note-taking-what-when-how-often/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to tell you about a little conversation I had with my friend Adrian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic was about how, when and what to log during a testing session regarding a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s see what came out of that talk…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started Running</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/16/how-i-started-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/16/how-i-started-running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to write about something non-technical. I would like to write about running and how I started it and what my experiences were with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tl;dr… here we go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the past influences the present</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/04/13/how-the-past-influences-the-present/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/04/13/how-the-past-influences-the-present/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only a quick rant about a discussion I overheard the other day…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a blog – Why long posts rarely work</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/13/how-to-write-a-blog-why-long-posts-rarely-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/13/how-to-write-a-blog-why-long-posts-rarely-work/</guid>
      <description>Hello.
So let’s clarify this… They rarely or ever work if you are a beginner blogger. If you have a reputation it will probably work or people will use it as a reference. But I’m skipping ahead.
Beginnings
When you are a beginner blog writer you want to get out as much content as possible. Write mostly relevant things and interesting information because you need to establish a name for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does it matter if I sit in an office or in a park</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/09/why-does-it-matter-if-i-sit-in-an-office-or-in-a-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/09/why-does-it-matter-if-i-sit-in-an-office-or-in-a-park/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
I’d like to explain a lot about a topic that is very near my heart. If your job is in an office you will understand this.
Why offices?
So why are we sitting together in one big place cramped up with 20-300 other people? Why bother the catering and the ventilation and what not to accommodate these people at one place? Why not just leave them be and let them work at home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I recruit – Why tool requirements are stupid</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/04/how-i-recruit-why-tool-requirements-are-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/04/how-i-recruit-why-tool-requirements-are-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Today I would like to write about something very interesting I’m seeing all over the place from recruiters. And that is tool requirements from developers.
For words
So why is it a problem that in a requirement from a developer there a lots of these:
– DB2
– QTP
– Ranorex
– Eclipse ( yes I saw a few of these… )
– Hibernate
– Grails
– Ruby on Rails</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should care about the quality of your test code</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/11/02/why-you-should-care-about-the-quality-of-your-test-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/11/02/why-you-should-care-about-the-quality-of-your-test-code/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today I would like to talk to you about something interesting I was talking about with a developer friend.
We talked about the quality of test code.
He said… And I will quote this…”Why should we care? It’s not production code. We aren’t giving it to the customer.”
There are a few reasons why you are going to get a slap in the face for a sentence like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Bit</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/10/11/diary-of-a-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/10/11/diary-of-a-bit/</guid>
      <description>————————-
Dear everbody.
I’d like to present you a small idea I was working on recently. The reminiscence of an old program. From the view point of the program.
I’m planning to put these out in few days successions.
I hope you enjoy it.
Cheers,
Gergely.
————————-
If I remember correctly it was the year 2012 when I was born. I’m unsure of this date as my subroutines and algorithms have been re-written so many times that if it weren’t for my backups I wouldn’t remember a thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s all about human interaction.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/31/its-all-about-human-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/31/its-all-about-human-interaction/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
Today I would like to write about something I experienced over the years of being in the software industry.
Some History
I’ve been a tester for a long time now. I’ve been up and down and down and up. I struggled for a very long time until I became somebody who I am today. And I still have many things to learn ahead of me.
I learned from many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Chaos There Shall Be Order</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/04/from-chaos-there-shall-be-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2013/01/04/from-chaos-there-shall-be-order/</guid>
      <description>Dear Readers.
Today I want to talk to you about something I discovered over years of working and experience.
Also something that I can see in the world repeating over and over again. Not just in Software business but also in History in Human nature in Physics and Systems.
So let’s see what I’m talking about.
What is Chaos?
Chaos is a state of utter confusion. Chaos is the opposite of order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a professional blog</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/how-to-write-a-professional-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/06/13/how-to-write-a-professional-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks.
I want to write a little bit about writing a professional blog.
Early steps
Let’s first talk about what you understand about professional blog. It’s either a semi professional one, that mixes life with professionalism, like chess, programming, testing, painting, drawing, engineering whatever your profession is. Or it can be a purely professional one without your life getting involved in it.
Either way you have to decide at the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello and welcome</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/26/hello-and-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2012/02/26/hello-and-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello Dear Visitor.
Welcome to the ramblings of a software test engineer who thinks that he is a tester but feels like a developer but works as a tester but wants to learn programming like a developer… And so on and so fort.
I will make a journey that has been done by many automation testers. The journey when you decide to step one forward. A friend of mine told me that it is good that a tester learns proper programming and that more should do so.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
