<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rambling on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/rambling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rambling on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/rambling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/09/07/i-used-to-have-great-ideas-on-the-toilet-but-i-no-longer-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/09/07/i-used-to-have-great-ideas-on-the-toilet-but-i-no-longer-do/</guid>
      <description>I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do. And I would like to reflect on that. So this is not going to be a technical post, rather some ramblings.
I already had a post similar to this one, but I failed to follow up on it, and now I&amp;rsquo;m re-visiting the question. With technology on the rise, embedded systems, chips, augmented biology and information being available at our fingertips, I have but one concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip for Debugging Headless Locally</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/22/quick-tip-for-debugging-headless-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/07/22/quick-tip-for-debugging-headless-locally/</guid>
      <description>If you are installing something with Packer and you have Headless enabled(and you are lazy and don&amp;rsquo;t want to switch it off), it gets difficult, to see output.
Especially on a windows install the Answer File / Unattended install can be like =&amp;gt; Waiting for SSH. for about an hour or two! If you are doing this locally fret not. Just start VirtualBox, and watch the Preview section which will display the current state even if it&amp;rsquo;s a headless install!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy building the future</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/19/busy-building-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/05/19/busy-building-the-future/</guid>
      <description>Fact is, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy.
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new job as a build engineer. As sort of a devops kind of guy. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely interesting considering that I made a career as a tester. Granted, I always was technical, and never really knew my path; but it seems my path is finding me after all.
In the past years, I got better at Docker, Puppet, Chef, AWS, Packer, Vagrant, Gradle, and a hell of a lot more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD is Dead – Not really</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/26/tdd-is-dead-not-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/26/tdd-is-dead-not-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is TDD dead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not really. So let&amp;rsquo;s talk about this topic for a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you already read a gazillion posts about this debate but frankly I&amp;rsquo;m writing this for myself, to rant a little bit, you know. Because somebody is wrong on the internet and I must intervene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking what when how often</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/20/note-taking-what-when-how-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/20/note-taking-what-when-how-often/</guid>
      <description>Hello Everybody.
Today I would like to tell you about a little conversation I had with my friend Adrian.
The topic was about how, when and what to log during a testing session regarding a story.
So let&amp;rsquo;s see what came out of that talk.
Logging your work
The question is really not whether you should log your work or not, but rather to what extend. Because we all know that you should log your work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started Running</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/16/how-i-started-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/05/16/how-i-started-running/</guid>
      <description>Hello Everybody.
Today I would like to write about something non-technical. I would like to write about running and how I started it and what my experiences were with it.
So tl;dr. here we go.
What led me to running
There were actually two things that led me to start running. Three.
Reason One: The accident
I&amp;rsquo;m a bike person by default. I *hate running with a passion. One day I was riding my bike in the woods when suddenly I hit a big ol&#39; tree trunk right head on at which moment my bikes front fork bent inwards and became completely useless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the past influences the present</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/04/13/how-the-past-influences-the-present/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/04/13/how-the-past-influences-the-present/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only a quick rant about a discussion I overheard the other day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a blog – Why long posts rarely work</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/13/how-to-write-a-blog-why-long-posts-rarely-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/13/how-to-write-a-blog-why-long-posts-rarely-work/</guid>
      <description>Hello.
So let&amp;rsquo;s clarify this. They rarely or ever work if you are a beginner blogger. If you have a reputation it will probably work or people will use it as a reference. But I&amp;rsquo;m skipping ahead.
Beginnings
When you are a beginner blog writer you want to get out as much content as possible. Write mostly relevant things and interesting information because you need to establish a name for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does it matter if I sit in an office or in a park</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/09/why-does-it-matter-if-i-sit-in-an-office-or-in-a-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/09/why-does-it-matter-if-i-sit-in-an-office-or-in-a-park/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to explain a lot about a topic that is very near my heart. If your job is in an office you will understand this.
Why offices?
So why are we sitting together in one big place cramped up with 20-300 other people? Why bother the catering and the ventilation and what not to accommodate these people at one place? Why not just leave them be and let them work at home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I recruit – Why tool requirements are stupid</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/04/how-i-recruit-why-tool-requirements-are-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2014/02/04/how-i-recruit-why-tool-requirements-are-stupid/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks!
Today I would like to write about something very interesting I&amp;rsquo;m seeing all over the place from recruiters. And that is tool requirements from developers.
For words
So why is it a problem that in a requirement from a developer there a lots of these:
 DB2 QTP Ranorex Eclipse ( yes I saw a few of these. ) Hibernate Grails Ruby on Rails .  Long answer</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
