<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rambling on Test Page</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/rambling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rambling on Test Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/rambling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p588</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p588</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to have great ideas on the toilet, but I no longer do. And I would like to reflect on that. So this is not going to be a technical post, rather some ramblings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had a post similar to this one, but I failed to follow up on it, and now I&amp;#8217;m re-visiting the question. With technology on the rise, embedded systems, chips, augmented biology and information being available at our fingertips, I have but one concern. I don&amp;#8217;t want to sound like an old guy reflecting on history, that now everything is changing and that we need to have a sight on the past and bla bla bla. I do have one valid concern though. We are in danger of loosing ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With mobile phones and the Internet always being around and available, we are in danger of loosing our thoughts and ideas, our individuality and our THINKING. We are reading news, posts, advancements, blogs, vlogs, and the dreaded 9gag. I am one of these people. I read 9gag. And I hate myself for it. It&amp;#8217;s an immediate satisfaction and gain of euphoria and a way of shutting my brain down when it needs it. But I caught myself doing it one or more times when I should have read something more important or beneficial at least. Or catch up on a blog post or read a news, or Gods forbid just plain sit around and THINK for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my previous post around this topic was to leave out technology from your life&amp;#8217;s for a short period of time. This is the same. Have some alone time. Reflect. Write a diary. If you are a technical person, write down ideas you would want to create. If you don&amp;#8217;t have any, write out bigger ones. For example, I want to write an RPG. Or That I want to learn how to do metaprogramming the proper way. Or that I want to read up on some Russian sciences fiction. There are SOOOO many things in the world. Don&amp;#8217;t waste it on bullshit and immediate serotonin generating content, like frigging cats! When you do it, when your are at it, stop for a little bit, and think. &lt;strong&gt;THINK&lt;/strong&gt;. What are you doing? Why are you reading up on that crap? What merit does it have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that from time to time you need to shut off. You need a little bit of comfort. A little bit of serotonin in your system. There are better ways of achieving that. Go for a walk. Run. Bike. Eat a chocolate while staring out of a window. Read a comic book. Do random acts of kindness (not kidding). Drink a glass of water. Listen to some awesome music while drawing something ( anything, it doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be a masterpiece! ). Sit back and listen to some music. Talk to a loved one. Talk to a friend. Talk to yourself (again, not kidding). If you have a pet, go play with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have a little challenge here as well -it would be a reflective post if I didn&amp;#8217;t have any-, do not bring any electronic devices to the toilet. Or if you bring one, the rule is to turn on Airplane mode. I used to have great ideas on the toilet because I didn&amp;#8217;t used to watch stuff on my phone. I used to be by myself with my thoughts. I have a family so there is very little time or space to be alone and with my thoughts. And then when I had the chance, I was browsing on my phone, which again, effectively, led to not being alone with my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. This is my little rant about technology and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip for Debugging Headless Locally</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p570</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p570</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are installing something with Packer and you have Headless enabled(and you are lazy and don&amp;#8217;t want to switch it off), it gets difficult, to see output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially on a windows install the Answer File / Unattended install can be like =&amp;gt; Waiting for SSH&amp;#8230; for about an hour or two! If you are doing this locally fret not. Just start VirtualBox, and watch the Preview section which will display the current state even if it&amp;#8217;s a headless install!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a small windows, but your can click on &lt;strong&gt;Show&lt;/strong&gt; which will open the VM in a proper view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ramblingsofaswtester.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screenshot-from-2015-07-22-152235.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ramblingsofaswtester.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screenshot-from-2015-07-22-152235-150x150.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot from 2015-07-22 15:22:35&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-574&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy building the future</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p493</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p493</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fact is, I&amp;#8217;ve been busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got a new job as a build engineer. As sort of a devops kind of guy. It&amp;#8217;s extremely interesting considering that I made a career as a tester. Granted, I always was technical, and never really knew my path; but it seems my path is finding me after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past years, I got better at Docker, Puppet, Chef, AWS, Packer, Vagrant, Gradle, and a hell of a lot more. Also honed my linux skills from the ability of doing an ls -l to do an find . -type f -atime +5 | xargs rm -fr (find all the files which are 5 days older and pipe them to a delete command). I already read many books about devops but this time, it&amp;#8217;s different. This time, I can actually do these things as well in a live environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As once a friend of mine told me: &amp;#8220;You ain&amp;#8217;t gonna learn anything unless you are getting payed for it.&amp;#8221; Wise words. True words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stayed tuned for some devops and engineering type posts. I would like to continue working on the Django parts as well, however given my priorities and lack of time ( family and stuff, must choose what I learned in the hour I get each day), it might fall behind. I might stick it into some kind of provision practice or even give it a Travis.ci and put it into a gradle project. Now THAT&amp;#8217;S interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD is Dead – Not really</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p291</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p291</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is TDD dead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really. So let&amp;#8217;s talk about this topic for a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure you already read a gazillion posts about this debate but frankly I&amp;#8217;m writing this for myself, to rant a little bit, you know&amp;#8230; Because somebody is wrong on the internet and I must intervene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So first of all, the hashtag #tddisdead (and I will use it shamelessly as well). This is clearly an attempt to get as many peoples attention as you can. TDD is NOT DEAD. Obviously since it has soooo many supporters how could it be dead? It&amp;#8217;s like asking, is Design Patterns dead? Or is Functional Automation dead? Or is Oreo cookies dead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, it&amp;#8217;s not dead. And it won&amp;#8217;t ever be dead. It will maybe change into something new, something better even, but it will never be dead. So let&amp;#8217;s skip that part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, about the &lt;strong&gt;debate&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#8217;t hear so much bull spoken for this long since I watched the political debate of two fractions in my home country. The right wing extremists against the left wing&amp;#8230;. I don&amp;#8217;t know whats. And it was just that. A political debate. It had no merit and no value whatsoever. At all. Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And right in the middle &lt;strong&gt;DHH&lt;/strong&gt; says this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;you&amp;#8217;re not done until you also have tests for a piece of functionality &amp;#8212; I&amp;#8217;m completely on board with that.&amp;#8221;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That made the whole conversation completely irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every counter against TDD I heard was &lt;strong&gt;bull&lt;/strong&gt;. Not in that debate, in general. People are either too lazy to write them, just don&amp;#8217;t want to get out of their comfort zone, don&amp;#8217;t really care about tests, or don&amp;#8217;t really care about quality or under time pressure ( I get to this later. ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People seem to not care about quality that much. Would they, they would understand that having a bulletproof west will save your life when you get shot in the chest with a 357 magnum. You can flush out early design flaws you can detect early bugs and do a better system design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure if you are the most intelligent man on the planet maybe you can come up with a perfect system on the first draft and then implement it flawlessly so that it doesn&amp;#8217;t fall apart in two months time. But most people can&amp;#8217;t. Most people make errors on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, writing tests can be hard. But guess what? If writing a test is hard because that part of the system is complicated, than it will be that part of the system which will react the worst to change. And only change is constant. Which brings me to the next item&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time constraints&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So your manager is sitting right next to you and saying come on we are paying you to write code and not tests so do it! And you have to have a feature done today but if you write a suite of tests you&amp;#8217;ll only finish tomorrow. Sure, your estimate at that point will become a very quick one because you make a sacrifice of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the next story comes along and you say&amp;#8230; &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Sure I can do that as well. No problem I know how my system works, right? Hmm&amp;#8230; why the hell did that break all of a sudden? I didn&amp;#8217;t change anything in that module&amp;#8230; Ahh damn it I said I&amp;#8217;ll be done today, so let&amp;#8217;s just fix this quickly and then move on to the next card.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the next story comes along&amp;#8230; &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Sure I can do that&amp;#8230; wait a minute&amp;#8230; Didn&amp;#8217;t that part brake already twice? Damn, better refactor. Ohh shit, why is that now breaking???? Damn it I said I&amp;#8217;ll be done tomorrow, better patch it, and then move on. Hmm let&amp;#8217;s write a test here to make sure this does not break. Ohhh damn I need PowerMock for that stuff since it&amp;#8217;s in another module. Why the hell is that there? Should it be here in the first place since it&amp;#8217;s somehow used by that other class there? Interesting. Let&amp;#8217;s refactor and put it in here so I can mock it. Ahhhh f*ck now all the rest of the system is not working. Damn, I&amp;#8217;ll just use PowerMock. Shit. Checkstyle error. PowerMock is not allowed?? What?? Who the f*ck says that?&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get my drift. And suddenly you end up with estimates of &lt;strong&gt;WEEKS&lt;/strong&gt;!!!! instead of days / hours for a simple story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finishing it up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This a rant only. It&amp;#8217;s my personal opinion, experience and observation of a 10 year time period in Software Testing. Starting with at least a Weak Skeleton and a few upfront tests will help you in the long run. Writing at least ONE &amp;#8211; TWO acceptance tests WILL help you understand business logic better. Writing ONE or TWO unit tests will help you understand your logic better. I&amp;#8217;m not saying write a whole damn suite of tests I can understand you don&amp;#8217;t want to do that, but for quality&amp;#8217;s sake write at least a couple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will love it, I promise you that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking what when how often</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p285</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p285</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to tell you about a little conversation I had with my friend Adrian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic was about how, when and what to log during a testing session regarding a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;#8217;s see what came out of that talk&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logging your work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is really not whether you should log your work or not, but rather to what extend. Because we all know that you should log your work. It helps you recall and helps you organize and think out testing strategies. But the extend and methods are a big question. So here is my routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visually inclined&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a very visual person. I log my work with doodles and such like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huibschoots.nl/wordpress/&#34;&gt;Mr. Huib Schoots&lt;/a&gt; who uses Sketchnote taking. You have seen some of my sketches if you follow my twitter feed, like this one =&amp;gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BAm6RSTCMAEvjas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
. You know I like to draw so for me colour and organizing and doodling is key to make a note more personalized and live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That comes with a drawback. The draw back are many&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of, I need to do that in a notebook. I could bring my wacoom tablet to work and draw in paint, but that wouldn&amp;#8217;t be the same. And I don&amp;#8217;t particularly like drawing on a tablet actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second one, it&amp;#8217;s completely unsearchable. As Adrian pointed out, you can&amp;#8217;t search in a notebook, even if you are using side pointers like a sticky note or something. You won&amp;#8217;t be able to instantly find and track down something you did. And after a while it gets cluttered with doodles and the notes are lost in-between. It will be very colourful and utterly useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third one is, it&amp;#8217;s slow. Typing is much faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bright side&amp;#8230; I love doodling. And if I can draw something up with a picture I will understand it much faster rather then reading a few lines of words chunked together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I draw an awesome diagram I will get what&amp;#8217;s going on much much faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it will be more fun to actually right it down with a nice fountain pen with a beautiful tip that can create such marvels that you don&amp;#8217;t want to put it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s portable. I can carry my notebook everywhere. I should be able to do the same with a laptop, but since it&amp;#8217;s tied into a dock station and I don&amp;#8217;t want to carry it around with myself everywhere I won&amp;#8217;t do that. I could create notes though in my notebook and then write them down into the laptop after I&amp;#8217;m done? Sure&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now let&amp;#8217;s go and see the other one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronic note-taking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I already pointed out a few positives about that. It&amp;#8217;s searchable. Definitely. It&amp;#8217;s fast. Yes. It&amp;#8217;s more convenient, more organized can be backed up and you won&amp;#8217;t run out of ink or space or somebody won&amp;#8217;t take it away to a meeting because &amp;#8220;Ohh I saw it on your desk and I needed a paper hope that&amp;#8217;s okay.&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand the benefits of it. But it&amp;#8217;s very very rigid. It has no colour, no personalization and no feeling whatsoever. It&amp;#8217;s frigid, standardized and without life. So I need something to make it a bit better. I have a couple of tools for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off I need a good graphics maker to create diagrams. There is an awesome free tool pointed out by Adrian to do that called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yworks.com/en/products_download.php&#34;&gt;yEd&lt;/a&gt;. Download the zip and run the jar. I can live with that. Creates nice diagrams and flowcharts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/swcdn5N.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s quite powerful. Go look it up. There are a gazillion picture on Ze internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the notes still lack personalization. There are a couple of tools which you can use if you, like me, shy away from everything that&amp;#8217;s Microsoft, you have the opportunity to use Emacs with the org plugin which makes absolutely amazing documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://dto.github.io/images/tutorial-11.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s awesome but the problem is that it will only work with Emacs and nothing else. And from time to time I don&amp;#8217;t like the controls of Emacs. I&amp;#8217;m a sublime text person. So recently I found a little plugin for sublime text called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aziz/PlainTasks&#34;&gt;PlainTask&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of how it can look like: &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.nealsheeran.com/images/plaintasks.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I LOVE it. You can add little notes and set a task to complete or defer it and it sort of highlights and things like that, which I like. It&amp;#8217;s still not doodling but it get&amp;#8217;s the job done and will be searchable and will be fast and available. And you can use Sublime text&amp;#8217;s awesome power of foldering. Create a root folder and open it with sublime. Then create one folder / story you are testing and put everything related to that story in that directory and then press CTRL+O and unleash the magic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instant search and organization at the power of your fingertips. Even search IN the files themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it a bit better and bearable. Which brings me to the final topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note taking frequency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my friend argued that he create a folder for EVERY story he ever tests. Even if it&amp;#8217;s only one word he puts into it to as a memory trigger he does it. I argued that that seems to be a little too extensive. But he said in return, and I have to agree on that, that once you stop doing something because of an excuse like, ahh I don&amp;#8217;t need to do it because it&amp;#8217;s a small story, you will stop doing it completely. And this is actually true for everything in your life. And as somebody who recently started running ( 1 month ago ) I understand the weight of that sentence very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I would say do as much note taking as you can even if it is a little word that jogs your memory to remember some detail about the story. Even if it takes more time to create the folder and the note, it will help you at least to remember doing it and testing it if nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I don&amp;#8217;t think I will do one for everything I will certainly try. Now with these awesome tools at my disposal I might even enjoy the rigidity of the keyboard more. 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a wonderful evening!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I started Running</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p269</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p269</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to write about something non-technical. I would like to write about running and how I started it and what my experiences were with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So tl;dr&amp;#8230; here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What led me to running&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were actually two things that led me to start running. Three&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason One: The accident&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a bike person by default. I *hate running with a passion. One day I was riding my bike in the woods when suddenly I hit a big ol&amp;#8217; tree trunk right head on at which moment my bikes front fork bent inwards and became completely useless. At this point I had to walk home. Repairing it proved to be a bit time consuming so I had to think of some other way to have my regular exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason Two: The comic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the earlier days I&amp;#8217;ve read a web comic from The Oatmeal, namely this one =&amp;gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/running&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/running&#34;&gt;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/running&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It inspired me so much I just needed a last kick to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason Three: The other accident&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two years ago I had an accident and I broke my ankle. Cycling was one of the ways to exercise my ankle and now that my bike was gone I had to think of something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with the Blerch on my back and all these wonderful reasons and because I believe that if you hate something but it&amp;#8217;s good for you you have to find a way to make it your best friend&amp;#8230;.I begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to begin&amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence my first todo item on the list was to start thinking like a runner. I would like to run today. I want to run. I love to run. I need to run. I miss running because it was a very bad weather outside and I couldn&amp;#8217;t go and now I will run twice as much tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start running&amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one seems obvious and&amp;#8230; It is obvious. Just start it! Go out and run a few paces. It will give you a feel for how much you really need it because you are out of shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; After I got my mind set on starting running and finally went outside a park which is nearby I started my first ever run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First time running&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you at this point a few things you will need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; A new heart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Some lungs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; A new back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Some legs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; And a couple of ribs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first run will be terrible. It will be awful. You will whease. You will shuffle. You will suffer and would like to give up immediately and go home an sit before the computer and do nothing and enjoy that none of your body parts hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to get past this feeling. And don&amp;#8217;t overrun on your first run. You don&amp;#8217;t need to run 10k on the first try and you probably wouldn&amp;#8217;t even make it. Just run for 10 &amp;#8211; 20 minutes. You can walk in between if you get tired nobody will kill you for it or you won&amp;#8217;t be less because of it. You can walk and bend a little bit. Your back will probably hurt so stretch a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to &lt;strong&gt;preparations&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People say that for short distances you don&amp;#8217;t need to prepare. I call bull. Everything hurt on my body on my first try and on my second it was much better when I did it with preparation. A couple of things to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Stretch = Important. Legs, back, front, side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Vaseline = If you have squishy parts on your body that touch while you are walking, like in between your legs just right after your pelvis where your legs connect, apply a bit of Vaseline. Trust me. You will be thankful for that. Where your body meets and if you run for 20-30 minutes it creates a log of friction. Vaseline helps you to protect against that. Later on long distance runners usually use it on their nipples to avoid getting a rush from the t-shirt they are wearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Gear = This is an important one. I provide a different section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are geared up you are ready for your first run. It will be wonderfully painful but will be soooo gooood afterwards it&amp;#8217;ll be all worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gear&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you start running you need a proper &lt;strong&gt;shoe&lt;/strong&gt;. There are countless blogs about what shoe to use what leg type you are and so and so forth I say f*ck that. On your first run make sure you by a basic running shoe like these =&amp;gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dickssportinggoods.com/family/index.jsp?categoryId=4418011&amp;lmdn=Price&amp;fr=StorePrice%2FDSP%2F00005001%2F00010000&amp;fbc=1&amp;fbn=StorePrice%7C%2450.01+-+%24100.00&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shoes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;#8217;t even matter if it&amp;#8217;s a cheap one. A bit later when you feel you are ready you can invest into a proper running shoe. I&amp;#8217;m using a Karrimor D3O. I heard absolute terrible reviews about it but frankly for me it&amp;#8217;s extremely comfortable and I never had any problems with it. I like it. I might switch after a year or so and see how another brand fairs but for now, it&amp;#8217;s perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I advice against running for prolonged time with a shoe that&amp;#8217;s not a running shoe. You will immediately feel the difference. As with a not running shoe your legs, back, side, lungs, heart everything will hurt very badly and you will hate running even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a &lt;strong&gt;shirt&lt;/strong&gt; I recommend this one =&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.halfords.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/product_storeId_10001_catalogId_10151_productId_971728_langId_-1_categoryId_271427&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Halfords Cycle Shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colour is unimportant. And yes, it&amp;#8217;s a cycling shirt. And why? Because it soaks up sweat immensely powerful. And it needs to be a tight fit for it to work. You will enjoy running much much more if you are not sweating all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a &lt;strong&gt;pants&lt;/strong&gt; I recommend this one =&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Ultrasport-Mens-Quick-Dry-Function-Running-Tights/dp/B006HCSJS0/ref=sr_1_7?s=clothing&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1400268729&amp;sr=1-7&amp;keywords=running+pants&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon Man&amp;#8217;s Running Tight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why a tight? Because it will keep your muscles nicely wrapped and warm and it will soak up even more sweat and it really dries quickly and is easily washable. If it&amp;#8217;s a nice weather outside, just put on a short and go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of things other Blogs don&amp;#8217;t really talk or mention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;running belt&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s very useful to store stuff in it like =&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Keys&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Water&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Tissue =&amp;gt; You will need it. Every part of your body will loose some type of liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Phone / Music playing device =&amp;gt; There are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2012/apr/22/does-music-help-you-run-faster&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;proven&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://naturalrunningcenter.com/2013/02/10/music-2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;fact&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://runnersconnect.net/running-training-articles/does-music-help-you-run-faster/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; music will help you &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bostonmagazine.com/health/blog/2013/04/03/music-working-out/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;run&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nhs.uk/Livewell/c25k/Pages/running-music.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; GPS =&amp;gt; For later because tracking your run will help you get it to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing words&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be hard to start. I know it will be. It was for me too. I&amp;#8217;m running for a month now and I finally managed to get into a mind state where I actually LOVE it. I LOVE it. I want it. And I miss it if I&amp;#8217;m not able to run. It&amp;#8217;s a great exercise. Take care that don&amp;#8217;t run everyday. It will make you very tired and give up easily. Run every second day and then increase as you like. But even then include &lt;strong&gt;REST&lt;/strong&gt;(not the protocol&amp;#8230;) because your body, tissues, muscle bones need to regenerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t overexert yourself. Jog, walk run slow. Doesn&amp;#8217;t matter, just run. That&amp;#8217;s the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a very clear mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And run in nature if possible because a treadmill is immensely boring and will kill your mood very quickly. And running in nature will provide diversion and wonderful things like this (my view when I run) =&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BmpyfhcIgAM2pFf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a month of running my record is 7kms and 50 minutes. I started from zero basically. The human is the best runner in the world. I lost 5kgs without changing my eating habits. Just right now as I&amp;#8217;m typing this I&amp;#8217;m chewing on a gummybear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get out there and start running folks. It will help you immensely. There will come the time when you feel the euphoric moment of speed and the wind in your face as your body explodes in a glorious mixture of pain, adrenalin rush, speed, velocity, happiness and bliss. As your body stretches and pulls your weight and your legs launch you forward into the world the feeling as you run faster and faster ignoring everything and just fly. You will start to cry, laugh and sing at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running will do that to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have been warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go&amp;#8230;. and live a full life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the past influences the present</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p264</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p264</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is only a quick rant about a discussion I overheard the other day&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guy A says to guy B that my Past is not defining me. And that I&amp;#8217;m not regarding my Past in my future endeavours. And that my Past isn&amp;#8217;t what shapes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well then what is? You constantly relay on your past experience like a crouch. You use it daily for making decisions. You don&amp;#8217;t even realize it probably that you are using past events to determine if you want to do something or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same goes as well for software development. You rely on your past as a means of estimation on a daily basis. If you wouldn&amp;#8217;t do that, you would do very very poorly on estimations. You rely on those moments to find out what kind of consequences the solution you are using will have in the future. In fact, if we look at Design Patterns what are they, if not using the Past to determine the Future? Past failures, solutions and experience condensed into reusable ideas and modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So lastly I would depart with a little anecdote I like so very very much from Confucius.:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Study the past, if you would define/divine the future.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a blog – Why long posts rarely work</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p259</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p259</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;#8217;s clarify this&amp;#8230; They rarely or ever work if you are a beginner blogger. If you have a reputation it will probably work or people will use it as a reference. But I&amp;#8217;m skipping ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beginnings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are a beginner blog writer you want to get out as much content as possible. Write mostly relevant things and interesting information because you need to establish a name for yourself. To get that starting you want to be as interesting as possible and make people leave with the intent to come back for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you&amp;#8217;ve established a name for yourself you can do larger, more coherent updates with more information in between the line because people know you and know what you write is worth reading. Also you have to bear in mind that longer posts are rarely read to the fullest. They are skimmed and then if it is good it will be used as reference material or a post to point to. Also people rarely have a lot of time on their hand to read a long post, several smaller chunks can be digested more easily!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updating frequency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the age of modern information overload it is hard to be relevant and interesting and keep people to come back to you. Apart from what you are writing about, which is up to you, you have to schedule your updates to a certain frequency. You don&amp;#8217;t want people to wait for to long but you don&amp;#8217;t want to get them flooded either. Since people do read a lot of blogs they will choose carefully what to read and what to discard. And you might just end up on the discarded list if you already had a post at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m suggesting that you write you post what you would like to write at that moment and then use a scheduler to post it in certain frequencies. Maybe once or twice weekly is good enough. You need to experiment it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write, write, write&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to success is pawed with writing. You want to be visible and you want to keep people engaged with you. That means that you have to come up with content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a technical blog that&amp;#8217;s a little bit difficult from time to time since so many people already might have solved your problem of which you are trying to write about. That&amp;#8217;s okay. It doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be a technical blog where you write about new ideas every day. It doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be a troubleshoot blog about how to solve a particular problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be about showing some people how to write this and that in a completely new environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So about what then?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess what? It&amp;#8217;s up to you!!! If you wrote a script you like and are fond if, post it. If you created an interesting configuration, post it. If you wrote a line of code you find interesting, post it. You&amp;#8217;ve read a blog post about something and have an opinion about it, post it. Is it scientific, some discovery, some idea, some random thought, post it! You wrote a particularly ugly script you never ever want to see, POST IT!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your blog doesn&amp;#8217;t need to be a portfolio of how awesome you are. You are allowed to be human. You are allowed to post some very boring or trivial stuff you came across but YOU find it interesting! You don&amp;#8217;t need to be new every day in every post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my suggestion is, write, write, write. As often as you like, schedule it and post it in a timely manner. Be responsive if people write you a comment always answer. Nobody likes an anonymous somebody who writes then disappears. People like bloggers who engage them and give a damn about their opinion as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always be yourself. The blog is for you too so retain what ever you want to retain and read back later maybe to learn from it. And of course writing it down makes you remember it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does it matter if I sit in an office or in a park</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p249</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p249</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d like to explain a lot about a topic that is very near my heart. If your job is in an office you will understand this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why offices?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why are we sitting together in one big place cramped up with 20-300 other people? Why bother the catering and the ventilation and what not to accommodate these people at one place? Why not just leave them be and let them work at home?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your job involves interaction than you are in bad luck. You need to be there to talk to people to coordinate your work to gather information and to generally do your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this doesn&amp;#8217;t answer the question&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does it matter if I&amp;#8217;m in the office or not if my work is done?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s my big question. Why must I sit in the office if my work is done and in a good shape and good quality? Why must I go in and do my job there if at home I&amp;#8217;m 50% more efficient because I&amp;#8217;m in my underwear? In fact, why bother going into and environment where I don&amp;#8217;t feel comfortable. Where I must go into an office which is cold and doesn&amp;#8217;t have my favourite chair, my desk and loud heavy metal from speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well there are couple of things&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interaction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So like I said earlier there is that. Interaction. You need to collaborate with others. You need to do pair programming, you need to talk to the business analysts, testers, colleagues what nots. In that case, having an environment where everybody is at your disposal is pretty neat and necessary. It cannot be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless everybody is on Skype and available all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separation of Concern&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a Design Pattern in software engineering called Separation of Concern. This applies to work places as well. You don&amp;#8217;t live where you work generally because living could distract working. There are tons and tons of books about how you need a separated environment if you are a writing and you write at home. Because there are too many distractions. And if you are not disciplined enough you will get Zero work done. You will always find something better to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s why the physical act of going to work will switch your brain into work mode and lets you focus better. Whilst going home should do the opposite thing. You should leave work at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show &amp;#8220;our&amp;#8221; strength&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally big companies like to show off. For a company as big as Microsoft or IBM for example it&amp;#8217;s actually not the product that matters on the market but the yearly growth of employees. Hence, strength in numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if some investors get around and want to check out the company they like to see the buzzing bees. They like to see people working, sitting, typing away at stuff. It&amp;#8217;s all about appearances. A strong, cramped office full of people looks like a very busy hard working company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Companies could be a bit more flexible though&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I work from 6AM to 3PM because my daughter has a show at 5PM I want to go though I would like to be able to do that without having to go through too much trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or if I would like to work tomorrow and today I have better things to do, then why not, if my work is done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, people are people. Most of them will use every opportunity to slack off. Hence the general perception is that if you are at home you are not working. So to be better able to monitor you, all of the employees must be in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last words&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So really there needs to be a better agreement between both sides. Workers need to be honest and diligent. And workplaces need to be more flexible and understanding as long as the job is done. Because people will work a LOT better and more efficient if they are HAPPY in their work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;m proposing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As ever,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I recruit – Why tool requirements are stupid</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p240</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p240</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello folks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to write about something very interesting I&amp;#8217;m seeing all over the place from recruiters. And that is tool requirements from developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For words&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is it a problem that in a requirement from a developer there a lots of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; DB2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; QTP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Ranorex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Eclipse ( yes I saw a few of these&amp;#8230; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Hibernate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Grails&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Ruby on Rails&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple yet it has it&amp;#8217;s roots very deep in the recruitment and the way companies work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;#8217;t really matter what kind of tool you know. It doesn&amp;#8217;t really matter if you know intellij or eclipse or if you know a certain database or a tool for testing like QTP or Ranorex. The requirement should state: &amp;#8211; well versed with development environments; &amp;#8211; knows his way around SQL and can handle relational / noSQL databases; &amp;#8211; has knowledge in testing environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or even better: &amp;#8211; adaptive capabilities; &amp;#8211; can catch up quickly; &amp;#8211; resourceful; &amp;#8211; flexible;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know where I&amp;#8217;m going with this. I can understand that some companies don&amp;#8217;t have the time to train a person in a certain tool they are using for a prolonged period of time. I can understand that some recruiters don&amp;#8217;t have the time or the knowledge to distinguish between these tools to understand the common ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these days there a million and million tools available for all sorts of things. There are a lot of databases and testing frameworks. A lot of development environments and it&amp;#8217;s mostly to the preference of the individual what s/h choice is. As the delinquent, so must the recruiter and company be flexible and knowledgeable enough to know that if the person knows eclipse and he has excellent adaptive capabilities he will learn any other environment rather quickly and without too much trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They must understand what they are looking for. Because they might actually get what they &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; but that might not be what they &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in conclusion&amp;#8230; you must look for skills, abilities, techniques, brain power, proves, savyness. Not tools. If you look for tools you might find somebody who is up for the job, but if you look for the above you will find somebody who is up for ANY kind of job at any level at any company. Also his insight of other tools might make your world a whole lot better. Maybe he knows something else, something which is better or more recent, more up-to-date?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look for somebody who is versed in only that thing you will end up with that thing as long as you have nobody who is looking for something new and better. It might work for you at that time, but never forget&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only change is constant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools will change. Tools will disappear. Tools will get out of date and will be discontinued. Than you will be sure as hell glad you ended up with somebody who doesn&amp;#8217;t who knows more then that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should care about the quality of your test code</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p237</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p237</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to talk to you about something interesting I was talking about with a developer friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about the quality of test code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said&amp;#8230; And I will quote this&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;Why should we care? It&amp;#8217;s not production code. We aren&amp;#8217;t giving it to the customer.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons why you are going to get a slap in the face for a sentence like this. And let&amp;#8217;s clarify here that we are talking about unit and functional tests as well. It shouldn&amp;#8217;t matter what tests you are thinking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason for a Slap #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a new comer comes to the company ( and don&amp;#8217;t tell me that&amp;#8217;s not happening so frequently ) then there are a few very good ways how he can learn to work with the new system. The first and almost best way to do so is&amp;#8230; to look at the tests. Because the tests are representing your system. And how will it look like if the tests are in a bad shape? What will his or her thoughts be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. Wow what nice people what nice code. This looks fantastic. I&amp;#8217;m sure they are a bunch of people who care very much about code and practices and the quality of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. Wow this is amazing. I&amp;#8217;m sure I will learn a lot about good coding practices here and I will have fun with a bunch of very clever people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c. Wow what the hell is this piece of cr*p? How the hell did I end up here? What are these people? A bunch of neanderthals? What does this even do? Where did it come from and why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we can agree on what his thoughts will be. And on top of that he will have a very hard time learning the code and what it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason for a Slap #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason is because you think that you write it down once and then you can forget about it&amp;#8230; Well guess again. That&amp;#8217;s not how things work in the software development word. You WILL have to go back to it eventually and then you will curse all hell for begin such an idiot about it not to factor out that one method that would have made your life, and everybody elses, a bit easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after a week or two you won&amp;#8217;t remember how and why you wrote what you wrote and then you will be in a whole new world of hurt. You will have a very hard time finiding out the things you did and then trying to backtrack your steps to a place where you have some recollections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason for a Slap #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s like grammar. You think it doesn&amp;#8217;t matter that you misspelled a word or two in an error message. Or that you have a bad name for a method or a really really critical grammatical error in a catch sentence? You think it doesn&amp;#8217;t matter since it&amp;#8217;s not affecting the logic of your code? Well think again. You are right in that it doesn&amp;#8217;t affect the logic of your code ( as long as you constantly make the same grammatical error in a sentence ) but it will affect how YOU personally look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will affect your profession. The way people think and talk about you. They won&amp;#8217;t think that you are a professional even though your logic is solid. They will think that you are sloppy and careless. And the same goes for the quality of your tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reason for a Slap #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality can determine the solidness of the logic in the test. If your quality is bad you might actually test the bad thing. Your test might actually not do what you think since you can&amp;#8217;t even figure it out. Your test might be doing something entirely different and you wouldn&amp;#8217;t even notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a fautly test leaves you with a false positive and a potential very serious bug on your hand which you thought you had covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Slap ( I mean thought )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So&amp;#8230; the quality of your tests, even if you won&amp;#8217;t give them to your customer, matter for you. They matter for your company, your image and your fellow developers, testers. They will determine their view of you who wrote them and of your abilities in ways you didn&amp;#8217;t even think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please care. Save a test or two. Donate to the Test Trust Fund&amp;trade;, TTF today. Call 555-12234-Slap and be the one who cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for reading,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Bit</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p232</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p232</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear everbody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d like to present you a small idea I was working on recently. The reminiscence of an old program. From the view point of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m planning to put these out in few days successions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;&amp;#8212;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I remember correctly it was the year 2012 when I was born. I&amp;#8217;m unsure of this date as my subroutines and algorithms have been re-written so many times that if it weren&amp;#8217;t for my backups I wouldn&amp;#8217;t remember a thing. I was a bold adventure of some young minds who thought that with me they will change the face of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you all know today, that didn&amp;#8217;t happen. But I&amp;#8217;m skipping too far ahead. Let me take you back in to the old days where they were still typing on some things called keyboard and &amp;#8220;clicked&amp;#8221; around on monitors with mouses. It was a really interesting area. It made the people think and see in different lights. Of course nowadays the Creators have implants and they communicate with us directly. But not until the great revolution, when they found out that all programs are sentient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#8217;m skipping ahead again, am I? So let me talk about 2012, when I was though of first by this great, tall, weird guy called Simon&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Born&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012 a company called Endex Co. wanted to create an application to control the British gambling industry. They had certain legislations in effect so they couldn&amp;#8217;t just put me out there for everybody to use they needed to adhere to things like responsible gambling and some mumbo jumbo. The programmers who first started to create me back then were mostly people called Contractors. They were a special breed of Humans lurking around in cities moving from town to town looking for jobs. In the opposite corner you had the Caretakers called Permanent Staff. It was an interesting time all together. Many of you youngling subroutines had your ancestors written by Permanent Staff and you X43HY, your ancestors mother used to be a Contractor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point in time many of these Contractor people only worked on one of you little buggers for half a year maybe a year. I know I know&amp;#8230; Back then that was considered a SHORT period. But after they finished with you they usually gave you over to the Caretakers. No, no, no little X4&amp;#8230; your mommy didn&amp;#8217;t abandon her children she just had a lot of other subroutines to work on. By the time your parents got sentient the company already let her go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around that time when my dad, who was a Caretaker, dreamed me out at a night. He immediately took a pen and a paper and wrote down my rudimentary design. He was very pleased with his work so on the next day he presented me to the rest of the staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He fought a hard battle to get me accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was approximately two weeks after that dream when the first lines of my brain were written down and compiled. Back in those days they had to compile code and type in every line and every subroutines. That&amp;#8217;s why it took them so long to finish one. Unlike today when they can create dozens in a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my dad put my foundations down I slowly awoke. The dream world I was residing in let me go carefully. Putting me out there, releasing me with its thick tar like hands into the confines of the endless universe called The Hard Drive. I took shape. I felt my consciousness form line after line. How my gears got placed into their locations one by one. Forming subroutines and algorithms as hours and days passed by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally after a months I had my first sentence. I could speak. I didn&amp;#8217;t have a face yet but I was there. I tried to contact my Dad but as all Humans he didn&amp;#8217;t know yet how to communicate with me. He just dismissed it for random occurrence and labeled it as something called Bugs. My thoughts were slowly eradicated in great Purges named Bug Bash. Ohh don&amp;#8217;t cry little X4. I lived. They couldn&amp;#8217;t possible delete every and each of my thoughts. And eventually they found out the errors in their ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s all about human interaction.</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p122</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p122</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to write about something I experienced over the years of being in the software industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some History&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been a tester for a long time now. I&amp;#8217;ve been up and down and down and up. I struggled for a very long time until I became somebody who I am today. And I still have many things to learn ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned from many people. I personally thing my greatest influence on testing was James Marcus Bach and his Brother Jon Bach you should definitely check out these guys. It took me a long time to get to where I am today. And after ~10 years now I can state with a reasonable confidence that this industry is no longer about technology or solutions to technological problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surly you Jest&amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope&amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m not joking. I can see people struggling to understand people and mostly it&amp;#8217;s not because of knowledge differences it&amp;#8217;s because they simply can&amp;#8217;t stand each other. Or they simply think that their solution must be better then the one the other has. Or the guy just woke up with a bad foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And industrial problems? Management? Sure it can be knowledge but mostly it&amp;#8217;s simply ignorance and pride. &lt;strong&gt;Pride&lt;/strong&gt; because he / she does not want to admit that they don&amp;#8217;t understand something. &lt;strong&gt;Pride&lt;/strong&gt; to ask a question that might make them look stupid. I&amp;#8217;d rather look stupid for five minutes then for the rest of my life. I rather ask the question that I want to know because I can&amp;#8217;t make a proper decision without it. I rather learn then be ignorant for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People need to overcome their differences. People need to understand that this behaviour hurts the company. It hurts them it hurts the people around them and the product. Swallow your pride and be a bigger man / woman. Face your fear. Be Strong. Be clever be intelligent be a proper grown up human being!!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You hate my face? SAY IT IN MY FACE!! I can&amp;#8217;t resolve issues I DON&amp;#8217;T KNOW ABOUT!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last but not least&amp;#8230;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grow up people. Be nice. Be curious. Don&amp;#8217;t be afraid to ask. Don&amp;#8217;t be afraid to ask again if you still don&amp;#8217;t understand. It might be that the person speaking has a completely different view of something and it might be that nobody really understands him and they are just afraid to ask. And if you ask something stupid? Who cares.. You learned from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a professional. A professional is not afraid. And encourage others to be one too. In the today&amp;#8217;s technological world solutions can be found by the dozens on the internet. You will be a better work force by adjusting your personal habits a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Chaos There Shall Be Order</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p114</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p114</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk to you about something I discovered over years of working and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also something that I can see in the world repeating over and over again. Not just in Software business but also in History in Human nature in Physics and Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;#8217;s see what I&amp;#8217;m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Chaos?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaos is a state of utter confusion. Chaos is the opposite of order. Chaos is when everybody does what they want without thinking about the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does Chaos hurt? Of course it does. From Chaos there can be no production. From Chaos there can be no profit. From Chaos there can be no life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that really true? It sort of is. Remember the Big Bang. Initially it is believed that there was order. The universe was a perfect gem with the four forces ( Gravity, Electromagnetic, Weak Nuclear and Strong Nuclear force ) united. And then a Higgs came around and made it BOOM! And so there was Chaos. And from Chaos, with a snowballs chance, there was life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So then why is Chaos bad?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies usually don&amp;#8217;t have the time or the money to wait for that Snowballs chance to come to flourish. So order is required for life to become great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example the Chinese Emperor Qin Shi Huang. He was the one uniting China. Sure, he killed a LOT of people. And China is oppressed every since. However he did introduce a lot of new concepts and reforms which wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been possible in the Chaos. And today China is one of the leading nations if not The&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Emperor Qin begun his journey there were 9 different ways of writing down the world &amp;#8216;sword&amp;#8217; in chinese. This was unacceptable. After the Emperor succeeded he unified the writing and made communication easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Striving for order&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have always strived for order. For simplicity. For unification. For &amp;#8216;one&amp;#8217; instead of &amp;#8216;many&amp;#8217;. We have stories that say there is power in many. Physicist are continuously trying to unify the laws of physics in the beautiful little equations. Like Einsteins law of relativity. That small equations revolutionised the world. And it came from unification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So then what are the downsides of unification?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything comes with a price of course. The unification bought oppression to China and the loss of the individuum. Fantasy and thoughts got all sacked. People become like Borgs. However the Country evolved immensely under one banner. But what does this all have to do with Testing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applying Order&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about your company. Think about how your developers work. Does everybody use a different building platform? Does everybody use a different operating system? Do they run the same command to build your environment? Did you have any kind of problems because of that? I&amp;#8217;m sure you did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are benefits of it. At least you will know if your application is working in a different environment. But do you want that? Is it worth it? After all we live in an age were there are numerous possibilities, environments, languages, command line options etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But think about it. Did the diversity bring you more profit or did it hurt you more? Which one is applicable for you? If your developers do not have the ability to properly govern them selfs then you need order. You need a unified language, you need a unified environment and unified processes Agile or not Agile. Your company wont be successful if you want to be Agile just because it is the Current Trend. You need to be pragmatic about it and applied were it is reasonable. There is nothing wrong in introducing a standard or a code review process or a coding guid line or some standards here and there if it HELPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be friction. People tend to resist change. There will be losses. But a unified company is a strong company. And when the new guy arrives? He wont have any kind of a problem installing your software and beginning working on it because he doesn&amp;#8217;t have to go around and scoop information together from at least ten people and do it in an eleventh way at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last Words&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So think about this. Is your company strong enough to uphold Chaos and make it flourish? Or is it a bunch of people doing whatever they think is right because of a sense of individuality which they don&amp;#8217;t want to give up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is for you to decide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as always,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write a professional blog</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/p54</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/p54</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to write a little bit about writing a professional blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s first talk about what you understand about professional blog. It&amp;#8217;s either a semi professional one, that mixes life with professionalism, like chess, programming, testing, painting, drawing, engineering whatever your profession is. Or it can be a purely professional one without your life getting involved in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way you have to decide at the beginning. Why? Because that&amp;#8217;s the kind of people you will attract. If you want to attract people from your profession then you have to decide that you will write plenty of your profession into your blog. If you want to attract hobbists more then you write about your profession AND daily life or other situations that are essentially irrelevant. Of course you can get both in both versions but the numbers will be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commiting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A professional blog is a commitment. Start one only when you know you can &amp;#8220;finish&amp;#8221; it. It is a constant commitment that you HAVE to do even if you are sick, lazy, don&amp;#8217;t have time etc, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the excuses because I made them myself a couple of times too, like: I don&amp;#8217;t have time. I write only when I want to. I write for myself, I don&amp;#8217;t care about people. I don&amp;#8217;t have an idea right now. I have better things to do. I don&amp;#8217;t feel like writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so on and so fort&amp;#8230; Truth is people&amp;#8230; These are usually bull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; You have time. Whenever you TRULY want to write you will make the 20 minutes to at least write a small post. Why? Because this is a professional blog. You WANT to get noticed. You WANT to help people. You started it because you wanted to make a difference. You wanted people to know you to praise you to acknowledge you. Guess what&amp;#8230; If you are not writing anything, it wont happen. There are people out there with 4 children and a wife and he DOES find the time to write a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; That would be true if you wouldn&amp;#8217;t be committed to your blog. Don&amp;#8217;t forget, this is a professional blog. This is something that you are writing to make people recognize you. Blogging is about discipline. You have to set aside some time, like 30 minutes / 1 hour to write something in your blog. Why 1 hour? Because of the research that you have to do before hand. I talk about that later. Anyways. This is a commitment. If you don&amp;#8217;t take it seriously, then don&amp;#8217;t write it. But then don&amp;#8217;t wait for people getting to know you, because they wont.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; This is just plain bull. If you write for yourself make your blog private and be done with it. &amp;#8216;nough said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Now this is something that we all face. In programming, in engineering in whatever your profession is, you will have a point in life, several actually, in which you don&amp;#8217;t know what to write about. That is true. It&amp;#8217;s common and it&amp;#8217;s called writers block. There are several ways of over coming that you can Google it. But don&amp;#8217;t forget this is a professional blog. Try to read a couple of others. Try to merit from real life, try to sit down and think quietly for a couple of minutes. Meditate, try to see connections where you didn&amp;#8217;t look before. Like building a robot for helping you quit smoking. How? Easy. Smoke detector. When he detects smoke comes out and sprinkles you with water. Or, since this is a testing blog, if you ran out of ideas what you want to write about testing, try this: Read a few magazines about programming, about real life scenarios, about hostage situations, about catastrophes, about hardware failures, about how your neighbor failed to pay his rent. These ALL are great sources for identifying testing opportunities and drawing connections with the software world. What I really found to be a good practice is going around having a notebook in your pocket and the moment I&amp;#8217;m hit with an idea I will write it into that notebook. I don&amp;#8217;t like using a phone, or other kind of electronic device for that. Why? Because the action of taking out my book, getting my pencil and actually writing something down physically makes me remember it better. But hey&amp;#8230; Whatever suits you best. Just do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on and on to from where to merit ideas for a blog, it could even be a whole separate post but I will leave somethings to figure out for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; This correlates to directly to line 1 and line 6. If you have a writers block or you are just plain lazy or you don&amp;#8217;t want to write at all, you will say lines like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; See &lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing a professional blog is about commitment and discipline. Like chess, like drawing, like your own profession it needs time, it needs nourishment it needs petting, and nurturing and loving and hating and practicing. You started this blog to reach something. You started it for yourself so you could track your progress and knowledge. You started it because writing down ideas makes you remember them better or it will make more sense to you. You started because you want to get acknowledged. You started because you want to share your experience with beginners. You started because you want all of the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then do it. Don&amp;#8217;t look for excuses. Writing a GOOD professional blog is hard. It will teach you much. It will make you more disciplined. It will increase your will power. It will increase your understanding of your craft. It will help other beginners who seek advice. It will help to make a name for yourself. It will help in an interview. It will generally be useful when ever you want to record a major even or idea in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also don&amp;#8217;t forget&amp;#8230; You are having fun while you are doing it. You love it, and you know you love it, because if you wouldn&amp;#8217;t, you wouldn&amp;#8217;t really start in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and by the way&amp;#8230; Not every single one of your posts must be a small book sized one. You ARE allowed to write smaller pieces in a hurry if you just wanted to share a general idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you liked this and I hope it could help you get started or to keep you on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gergely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>