<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>android on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sphere Judge Online – Python Kivy Android app – Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/03/02/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/03/02/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Here we are again. I will attempt to further this little journey of mine into the land of Android and Python.
This is the second part of the advanture you can read the first one a little bit back.
The Script We left off at a point where I successfully configured my environment and compiled my first hello world APK. At that point it took a little bit fiddling to get it to work on my phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sphere Judge Online – Python Kivy Android app</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/26/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/02/26/sphere-judge-online-python-kivy-android-app/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks.
Today I would like to take you on a journey I fought myself through in order to write a python android app, which gets you a random problem from Sphere Judge Online. Then you can mark it as solved and it will be stored as such, and you can move on to the next problem. With the words of Neil deGrasse Tyson, Come with Me!
Beginnings When I first embarked on this endeavour I ran into numerous errors, many amongst them being compilation issues when I was trying to install libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Web Framework – Meteor</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/29/javascript-web-framework-meteor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2015/01/29/javascript-web-framework-meteor/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
This time I would like to write about something that interests me. I wanted to try out a pure JavaScript web framework.
My choice is: Meteor. Looks interesting enough and it was recommended by a friend of mine. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.
Installation As always, one starts with installation. The page tells us to follow this simple step:
curl https://install.meteor.com/ | sh Easy enough, when you are on Linux. Turns out, that there is no official release yet for Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
