<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetup on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetup on Ramblings of a cloud engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 23:01:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Budapest Meetup</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/02/06/go-budapest-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 23:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2018/02/06/go-budapest-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/go-budapest&#34;&gt;Go Budapest Meetup&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, where the brilliant &lt;a href=&#34;https://jbrandhorst.com/&#34;&gt;Johan Brandhorst&lt;/a&gt;
gave a talk about his project based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://grpc.io/&#34;&gt;gRPC&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/improbable-eng/grpc-web&#34;&gt;gRPC-web&lt;/a&gt; +
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gopherjs/gopherjs&#34;&gt;GopherJS&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/protobuf&#34;&gt;protobuf&lt;/a&gt;. He also has some Go
contributions and check out his project here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/johanbrandhorst/protobuf&#34;&gt;Protobuf&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s GopherJS Bindings for
ProtobufJS and gRPC-Web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to see where these projects could lead and I see the potential in them. I liked the usage of Protobuf and gRPC,
I don&amp;rsquo;t have THAT much experience with them. However after yesterday, I&amp;rsquo;m eager to find an excuse to do something with these libraries.
I used gRPC indirectly, well, the result of it, when dealing with Google Cloud Platform&amp;rsquo;s API. Which is largely generated code through
gRPC and protobuf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also presented a bi-directional stream communication between the gRPC-web client and the server which was an interesting feat
to produce. It did involve the use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://godoc.org/golang.org/x/sync/errgroup&#34;&gt;errgroup&lt;/a&gt;. Which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t look THAT much into WebAssembly however, again, after yesterday, I will. He gave a shout out to WebAssembly developers
that he is ready to tackle the Go bindings for WASM!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a good change of pace to look at some Go code being written, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to visit the meetup again, in about three months
when the next one will come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, I&amp;rsquo;ll even give a talk if they are looking for speakers. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emarsys.com/en/about-us/&#34;&gt;Emarsys Budapest&lt;/a&gt; for organizing the event and bringing Johan to us
for his talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, &lt;br&gt;
Gergely&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
