<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on Ramblings of a build engineer</title>
    <link>https://skarlso.github.io/categories/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on Ramblings of a build engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 09:23:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://skarlso.github.io/categories/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/04/16/building-furnace-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 09:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/04/16/building-furnace-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1. Part 2. Part 3.
In this part we are going to talk about Unit Testing Furnace and how to work some magic with AWS and Go.
Mock Stub Fake Dummy Canned  Unit testing in Go usually follows the Dependency Injection model of dealing with Mocks and Stubs.
## DI
Dependency Inject in short is one object supplying the dependencies of another object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/22/building-furnace-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 12:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/22/building-furnace-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1. Part 2.
In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the experimental plugin system of Furnace.
Go Experimental Plugins Since Go 1.8 was released, an exciting and new feature was introduced called a Plug-in system. This system works with dynamic libraries built with a special switch to go build. These libraries, .so or .dylib (later), are than loaded and once that succeeds, specific functions can be called from them (symbol resolution).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/19/building-furnace-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 12:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/19/building-furnace-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hi folks.
Previously on this blog: Part 1.
In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the AWS Go SDK and begin do dissect the intricacies of Furnace.
AWS SDK Fortunately, the Go SDK for AWS is quiet verbose and littered with examples of all sorts. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it less complex and less cryptic at times. I&amp;rsquo;m here to lift some of the early confusions, in hopes that I can help someone to avoid wasting time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furnace - The building of an AWS CLI Tool for CloudFormation and CodeDeploy - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/16/building-furnace-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 21:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2017/03/16/building-furnace-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Building Furnace: Part 1 Intro Hi folks.
This is the first part of a 4 part series which talks about the process of building a middlish sized project in Go, with AWS. Including Unit testing and a experimental plugin feature.
The first part will talk about the AWS services used in brief and will contain a basic description for those who are not familiar with them. The second part will talk about the Go SDK and the project structure itself, how it can be used, improved, and how it can help in everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft world automatic backup to AWS S3 bucket - Part 2 (Custom functions)</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/17/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/17/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got an update for the backup script. This time, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the ability to implement your own upload capabilities. I provide a mock implementation for the required functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the script again, now modified and a bit cleaned up. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minecraft world automatic backup to AWS S3 bucket</title>
      <link>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/16/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skarlso.github.io/2016/04/16/minecraft-server-aws-s3-backup/</guid>
      <description>Hi Folks.
Previously we created a Minecraft server using Docker. After my server got popular in the family, and a lot of stuff started to pile up on it, as a good IT person, I&amp;rsquo;m backing up the world once in a while.
For that, I&amp;rsquo;m using AWS S3 with the CLI and a little bash script which runs once a week.
The script is really straightforward. I&amp;rsquo;m doing manual versioning, although S3 does provide one out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>